我们完全否认一切外部的战争和冲突,
We utterly deny all outward wars and strife,
以及为了任何目的
and fighting with outward weapons,
或以任何借口而用外部武器进行战斗,
for any end, or under any pretense whatsoever;
这是我们对世界的见证。
this is our testimony to the world...
这是“和平证词”，
This is the "peace testimony,"
1660年首次宣布为英格兰国王查理二世
first proclaimed in 1660 to king charles ii of england
由 George Fox 带领的一群宗教探索者
by a group of religious seekers led by George Fox
自称为“光明之子”
and calling themselves the "children of light",
或者“真相出版商”
or "publishers of truth."
对他们的批评者来说，他们被称为“贵格会教徒”
To their critics they were known as "Quakers,"
他们毫不掩饰地承认的嘲弄性的绰号
a derisive nickname that they unabashedly acknowledged
因为他们在酒精的影响下颤抖而闻名
as they were known for trembling under the influence
在他们的崇拜会议的圣灵。
of the Holy Spirit in their worship meetings.
最终，他们将正式命名自己
Ultimately, they would officially name themselves
“友朋会”
"The Religious Society of Friends."
他们富有远见的领袖乔治 · 福克斯在1683年写道:
Their visionary leader, George Fox, wrote in 1683:
“上帝创造了一切,
"God, who made all,
把祂的灵魂倾注在世界上所有的男人和女人身上,
pours out his spirit upon all men and women in the world,
在他新约的日子里,
in the days of his new covenant,
是的，在白人和黑人，荒原，土耳其人和印第安人,
yea, upon whites and blacks, moors, and turks, and Indians,
基督徒，犹太人，外邦人，都带着上帝的精神,
Christians, Jews, and gentiles, that all with the spirit of God,
可能知道上帝和上帝的事情,
might know God and the things of God,
在精神和真理上服务和崇拜。”。
and serve and worship, in spirit and truth".
成为模式，成为所有国家的榜样,
Be patterns, be examples in all countries,
地方，岛屿，国家，无论你来到哪里,
places, islands, nations, wherever you come,
你的马车
that your carriage
生命可以在各种各样的人中传道,
and life may preach among all sorts of people,
和他们;
and to them;
然后你就可以高高兴兴地走遍世界,
then you will come to walk cheerfully over the world,
回答每一个上帝的问题。
answering that of God in every one.
每个人心中都有上帝，就像它最初被使用的那样,
That of God in everyone as it was originally used,
其实指的是被制造出来的人
really referred to people being made
以上帝的形象和肖像。
in the image and likeness of God.
我们都有同一个父亲，同一对父母。
We all share the same Father with the same parents.
我们都是上帝的孩子,
We're all children of God,
我们都是同一个上帝的孩子。
we're all children of the same God.
我们需要认识到这就是我们需要回应的
We need to recognize that that's what we need to be responding to
在其他人身上，这就是共同的人性
in other people, is that common humanity
我们所拥有的，基督的内在之光。
that we have, the inward light of Christ.
就像太阳的光芒
And just as the light from the sun
让我们用眼睛看，我们的外在的眼睛,
allows us to see with our eyes, our outward eyes,
我们有向内的眼睛
we have inward eyes
当我们被上帝内在之光照亮时,
and when we are illuminated by that inward light of God,
我们可以看到我们的精神状态
we can see our spiritual condition
明白上帝要我们做什么。
and understand what it is God's calling on us to do.
随着运动数量和势头的增加,
As the movement grew in number and momentum,
内心的光引导贵格会成为关键角色
that inner light led Quakers to pivotal roles
在许多最具变革性的时刻
in many of the most transformative moments
在过去的四个世纪里。
of the last four centuries.
贵格会教徒，如威廉潘，苏珊·安东尼，露迪雅莫特,
Quakers such as William Penn, Susan B. Anthony, Lucretia Mott,
约翰 · 伍尔曼和乔治 · 吉百利
John Woolman and George Cadbury
获得了一定程度的名声,
have achieved a degree of fame,
但对其他成千上万的朋友知之甚少,
but less is known about thousands of other Friends,
比如那些来自美国中西部的,
such as those from the American midwest,
他们对贵格会理想的忠诚
whose faithfulness to Quaker ideals
对整个社会产生了积极的影响。
positively impacted the larger society.
这些是以前没有讲过的故事
And these are the previously untold stories
一些和平与平等的建筑师。
of some of those architects of peace and equality.
贵格会教徒在17世纪离开英格兰
Quakers left England in the 17th century
在新世界建立殖民地
to establish a colony in the new world -
William Penn 的“神圣实验”-
William Penn's "Holy Experiment" -
受到生活在可以被统治的地方的启发
inspired by the idea of living where they could be governed
根据他们的信仰。
according to their faith.
国王查理二世把这块土地赐给了佩恩
Penn had been given the land by King Charles II
解决一大笔家庭债务。
to settle a large family debt.
所以在1682年，他横渡大洋
So in 1682, he sails across the ocean
和一群殖民者在一起，他们大部分是贵格会教徒。
with a group of colonists, most of whom are Quakers.
但他没有对已经住在那里的人说,
But he doesn't say to the people already living there,
“这是我的”
"This is mine."
他说: “我要买下它。”
What he says is, "I am going to buy it.",
他不仅对瑞典人和荷兰人这么说。
he says this not only to the Swedes and the Dutch.
他对印第安人也这么说。
He says it to the Indians as well.
他说，这是我们想要定居的土地。
He says, "This is land that we want to settle on.
我们承认这是你们的土地
"we recognize it as your land
我们会向你们购买
and we will purchase it from you,"
首先是条约的数量
and begins, the first are the number of treaties
潘和他的儿子们和印第安人一起买地
that Pen and his sons make with the Indians to buy land
国王已经给了宾夕法尼亚大学。
that the king has already given to Penn.
在遇到佩恩之后,
After an encounter with Penn,
特拉华土著酋长 Tamanend 宣称:
Tamanend, a native american delaware chief, declared:
我们会爱上 William Penn
"We will live in love with William Penn
和他的孩子只要小溪和河流流淌,
and his children as long as the creeks and rivers run,
只要太阳，月亮和星星还在。
and while the sun, moon, and stars endure.
这部宪法是佩恩写的
Penn writes this constitution
允许人们自由崇拜,
allowing people freedom to worship,
废除死刑，除非..
abolishing the death penalty except in some very--
我认为如果你犯了叛国罪你还是会被处死,
I think if you engaged in treason you still be executed,
但除此之外，这是一份惊人的自由主义文件
but beyond that, this was an amazingly liberal document
他拼凑起来的。
that he put together.
宾夕法尼亚州的贵格会教徒聚居地,
The Quaker colony, Pennsylvania,
向所有人开放，并受法律管辖
was open to all and governed with laws
建立在平等、真理、简单与和平的基础上。
based on equality, truth, simplicity and peace.
和平需要正义，正义需要法律。
Peace requires justice, justice requires law.
法律要求政府,
law requires government,
不仅在国家内部，而且在国家之间。
not only within nations but also between nations.
William Penn 1693年。
~~ william penn, 1693.
如果你能建立一个国家
If you could only build a state
在那里人们可以自由,
where people would be free,
他们可以有宗教自由,
they could have freedom of religion,
他们可以有表达自己的自由,
they could have freedom to express themselves,
可以有平等,
there could be equality,
女人可以和男人一样平等，可以拥有同样的权利,
women could be as equal as men, could have the same rights,
可以做和人类一样的事情,
could do the same things as men,
不再需要拥有奴隶,
there would be no need to own slaves,
每个人都会以自己的方式给予社区,
that each in their own way would give to the community,
你会有一个公正的政府,
that you would have a just government,
照顾社会上的每一个人。
that would look out for everyone within the society.
不幸的是，到了美国独立战争时期,
Unfortunately, by the time of the American revolution,
在宾夕法尼亚州，非贵格会教徒比贵格会教徒多,
there were more non-Quakers than Quakers in Pennsylvania,
神圣的实验结束了
and the Holy Experiment came to an end
贵格会被投票淘汰
as Quakers were voted out of office
或者离职，而不是参与决策
or left office rather than participate in decisions
与制造战争有关。
related to war-making.
他以为他要建立一个乌托邦,
He thought he was going to establish a utopia,
一个人间天堂，却发现生活的残酷现实
a heaven on earth and found out that the tough realities of life
真的很碍事。
really get in the way.
但他确实创造了这个殖民地，他创造了这个模型。
But he did create this colony, he created this model.
我们有宗教自由的典范
We have the model of religious freedom
佩恩在宾夕法尼亚州建立的。
that Penn establishes in Pennsylvania.
还有 Unites States 的宪法,
And the constitution of the Unites States,
在某种程度上借鉴了他在17世纪80年代写的东西,
in some ways draws on things that he wrote in the 1680s,
将近100年前。
almost 100 years earlier.
虽然他们不再是宾夕法尼亚州的多数党,
Though they were no longer a majority in Pennsylvania,
贵格会教徒遍布美洲殖民地
Quakers had spread throughout the American colonies
在新泽西州的罗德岛有大量定居点,
with substantial settlements in rhode island, New Jersey,
弗吉尼亚州，南北卡罗来纳州和乔治亚州。
Virginia, North and South Carolina, and Georgia.
随着新大陆殖民地的发展,
As the colonies in the new land developed,
奴隶制成为经济体系的一部分。
slavery became a part of the economic system.
但贵格会教徒走上了一条不同的道路。
But Quakers were to follow a different path.
整个18世纪，朋友们鼓励那些拥有奴隶的成员
Through the 1700s, friends urged their members who owned slaves
解放他们，为他们的福利做好准备
to free them and make provisions for their welfare
到1784年基本上没有贵格会教徒拥有奴隶。
and by 1784 virtually no Quakers owned slaves.
奴隶经济在南方变得强大,
The slave economy became strong in the south,
所以在1806年，我的贵格会家族
so in 1806 my family group of Quakers
从 North Carolina Piedmont 地区搬到俄亥俄州。
move from the North Carolina Piedmont area, to Ohio.
他们不想在那个奴隶制社会中养育自己的孩子。
They did not want to raise their children in that slave society.
所以这是一个有意识的问题，也是一个经济问题,
So it was a matter of conscious and also a matter of economics,
寻找更好的生活
a matter of looking for a life that would be better
为了他们的社区和家庭。
for their community and their families.
他们被周围残酷的奴隶制吓坏了,
Appalled by the cruelty of slavery around them,
被这种可能性所吸引
and attracted to the possibility
生活在禁止奴隶制的地方,
of living where slavery was prohibited,
许多南方贵格会教徒开始迁移
many southern Quakers began moving
西北地区,
to the northwest territory,
首先定居在土地上，现在包括
settling first on land that now includes
俄亥俄州和印第安纳州。
the states of Ohio and Indiana.
1787年国会通过了西北法令,
In 1787 congress passed the northwest ordinance,
为政府的组织提供条件
which was to provide for the organization of government
以及俄亥俄河以北土地的定居。
and settlement of the lands north of the Ohio river.
什么可能是条例中最好的元素;
What was probably the best element of the ordinance;
然而，它的条款是否规定两者都不是奴隶制
however, was its provision that neither slavery
也不是强制劳役
nor involuntary servitude
将永远存在于西北地区的土地上。
would ever exist in the lands of the northwest territory.
朋友是被领土吸引的
And Friends are drawn toward territories
奴隶制是非法的。
where slavery is illegal.
丹尼尔 · 布恩在宾夕法尼亚贵格会长大,
Daniel Boone, who grew up a pennsylvania Quaker,
是那些帮助朋友搬到西部的人之一
was among those who helped friends move west
寻找一个安居乐业的地方。
in search of a place to live in peace and equality.
愿和平从她的天国降临,
Let peace, descending from her native heaven,
使她的橄榄在欢乐的民族中春天来临;
bid her olives spring amidst the joyful nations;
还有很多，和商业结盟,
and plenty, in league with commerce,
从她丰盛的手散布祝福！
scatter blessings from her copious hand!
丹尼尔 · 布恩，1784年。
Daniel Boone, 1784.
1799年，两个贵格会家庭
In 1799, two Quaker families
来自南卡罗莱纳州的布什河定居在“军事领地”
from bush river, south Carolina, settled on "Military Lands"
在俄亥俄州西南部，华盛顿堡北部,
in southwestern Ohio, just north of fort Washington,
几年后,
the site of what would, in a few years,
成为辛辛那提繁荣的河港城市。
become the thriving river port town of Cincinnati.
1803年，更多迁徙的朋友加入了我们,
In 1803, joined by more migrating Friends,
他们建立了第一个正式承认的
they established the first formally recognized
贵格会教徒聚会做礼拜，或者叫做“教堂”
Quaker meeting for worship, or "church",
在俄亥俄州西南部:
in southwestern Ohio:
在韦恩斯维尔举行的迈阿密月会。
Miami monthly meeting in the village of Waynesville.
同一年，发生了一些事
And that same year, something was to happen
回到南卡罗来纳州的布什河
back in bush river, south Carolina
这将为贵格教徒的迁徙打开闸门
that would open the floodgates for Quaker migration
西北地区。
to the northwest territory.
撒迦利亚 · 迪克斯，贵格会教徒,
Zachariah Dix, a Quaker,
那些听到他讲话的人所描述的,
described by those who heard him speak,
“一个强有力的狂想传教士”
as "a powerful rhapsodical preacher"
“以不同寻常的程度预见未来”
with "prophetic insight in an unusual degree,"
传达了一个令人不安的信息。
delivered a disturbing message.
到了18世纪90年代，《老友记》开始相信
By the 1790s, Friends had come to believe
Zacharias 有预言的天赋。
that Zacharias had a gift of prophecy.
他能看穿人们的思想
That he could see into people's minds
了解他们隐秘的精神状态。
and understand what their secret spiritual states were.
他对未来有预兆。
And that he had foreshadowings of the future.
当朋友们记录他的讲道时
As friends recorded their memories of his preaching
几十年后，撒迦利亚对他们说的话
decades later, what Zacharias had to say to them
是这样的“你有祸了，灌木河。
was something like this, "Woe unto thee bush river.
你荣耀的花朵已经凋谢。
The flower of thy glory has faded.
滚出这埃及奴隶之地
Get thee, hence, out of this land of egyptian slavery
黑暗笼罩着西北的自由土地”
and darkness unto the free lands of the northwest."
几年之内，一个教友会团体,
And within a few years, a Quaker community that had numbered,
大概有近1000人,
probably close to 1000 people,
在南卡罗来纳州只剩下不到一百人。
was fewer than a hundred left in south Carolina.
来到中西部的贵格会教徒
The Quakers who came here to the midwest
是那些更喜欢冒险的人。
were those who were maybe more risk-takers.
他们离家出走,
They left homes,
建立良好的农场和村庄
well-established farms and villages
家庭搬回东部，搬到西部。
and families back east and moved west.
很多贵格会教徒留在了东部,
A lot of Quakers stayed on the east,
他们的农场和家庭所在的地方,
you know, where their farms and families were,
他们做得很好,
and they did good work there,
但是那些来到西部的人,
but the ones who came west,
冒着各种风险和机会,
took all sorts of risks and chances,
我突然想到，我们可能对他们知之甚少
and it strikes me, we may know less about them
因为他们是实干家而不是作家。
because they were doers more than writers.
他们没有必要坐下来写下他们做了什么,
They didn't necessarily sit and write down what they had done,
他们就在外面做这个。
they were out there just doing it.
大量的贵格会教徒继续迁徙
A large number of Quakers continued migrating
今天的印第安纳州和俄亥俄州就像那些来自布什河的人一样,
to present-day Indiana and Ohio just like those from bush river,
忠实地遵循他们内心之光的指引。
faithfully following guidance from their inner light.
无论贵格会教徒在哪里组成团体,
Quakers wherever they form communities,
首先形成了一个崇拜的集会。
first formed a meeting for worship.
接下来他们做的事情是为他们的孩子开办一所学校。
The next thing they did was to open a school for their children.
那些贵格会学校经常招收非贵格会学生。
Those Quaker schools are often admitting non-Quaker students.
他们中的一些人获得了这样的名声
And some of them gained a reputation as being
中西部一些最好的中学。
some of the best secondary schools in the midwest.
1803年建州后,
After statehood in 1803,
建立了公立学校系统,
a public school system was set up,
但是黑人孩子不能参加。
but black children were not admitted to it.
尽管黑人地主被迫纳税
Even though black landowners were forced to pay taxes
资助公立学校,
that subsidized the public schools,
他们的孩子不能上那些学校。
their children could not attend those schools.
所以如果黑人孩子接受教育,
So if black children were to be educated,
也就是说他们的父母或者有同情心的白人
that means that their parents or sympathetic whites
必须让这一切成为可能。
had to make that possible.
在 Harveysburg
In Harveysburg,
离韦恩斯维尔只有几英里,
which is just a few miles from Waynesville,
那里有一个贵格会会议,
there was a Quaker meeting there,
有两个贵格会教徒,
and there were two Quakers,
elizabeth Harvey 和她丈夫。
Elizabeth Harvey and her husband.
他们在俄亥俄州为有色人种儿童创立了第一个,
They started the first for children of color in Ohio,
这在当时是闻所未闻的,
which was early and really unheard of at the time,
而且非常不满意，并且受到了很多人的批评
and highly frowned on and got a lot of criticism from people
他们不是朋友。
who weren't friends.
真正滋养自由的东西之一
One of the things that really feeds freedom
不是一个可以躲藏的地方而是一个可以学习的地方,
is not a place to hide but a place where you can learn,
一个你可以成为经济共同体的一部分的地方,
a place where you can become a part of the economic community,
为你的家人建造一个家,
build a home for your family,
然后把你的孩子送回学校。
and then send your children back to school.
哈维斯堡为黑人学生创办了一所学校
And Harveysburg created a school for black students
甚至雇佣黑人和白人教师。
and then even hire black and white teachers.
所以它很重要，因为它从基地开始。
And so it was important because it started at the base.
对于早期的朋友来说,
For early friends of course,
这只是普通的经文。
this is just plain scripture.
平等是..。
Equality is...
你看保罗的书信
you look in the epistle from Paul
上面说在基督里没有男女之分,
and it says in christ there is no male or female,
没有希腊人或犹太人，没有奴隶或自由。
there is no Greek or Jew, there is no slave or free.
如果我们是基督身体的一部分，我们都是一样的
If we are part of the body of christ, we are all the same
因此，社会的区别
and so the social distinctions that were made
并且仍然在一定程度上
and still are made to a degree
不同背景的人之间
between people of different backgrounds
还有不同的性别，这些都无关紧要。
and different genders, those are all irrelevant.
这些都是外在的东西，但内在的我们都是,
Those are all outward things, but internally we are all,
就像我说的，上帝的孩子们,
as I said, children of God,
都是上帝的子民。
and are all equally children of God.
随着越来越多的国家
As more and more of the country
开始依靠奴隶劳动来提高生产力和节约成本,
began relying upon slave labor for productivity and cost savings,
整个西北地区的贵格会教徒
Quakers throughout the northwest territory
继续做出艰难而危险的选择
continued to make the difficult and dangerous choice
支持所有人的自由。
of supporting freedom for all.
Christopher Anthony 贵格会的创始人之一
Christopher Anthony, a founding member of the Quaker meeting
在俄亥俄州的辛辛那提,
in Cincinnati, Ohio,
是众多放弃依赖奴隶劳动的贵格会教徒之一。
was one of many Quakers to give up his reliance on slave labor.
玛丽 · P · 哈特是克里斯托弗 · 安东尼的孙女,
Mary P. Hart was Christopher Anthony's granddaughter,
幸运的是，她有能力分享她的记忆
and fortunately, she had the wherewithal to share her memories
以及她家族的一些口述历史
of the meeting house and some of the oral history of her family
以及他们是如何到达辛辛那提的。
and how they came to arrive in Cincinnati.
”家庭用品都是马车运来的
"The household goods came in Wagons
还有一个黑人家庭。
and with them a family of negroes.
这个人是祖父的一个奴隶的后代
The man was a descendant of a slave of grandfather's
在祖父加入朋友会之前,
before grandfather joined the Society of Friends,
那时他释放了所有的奴隶”。
at which time he set all his slaves free".
~ Mary P. Hart.
即使是贵格会教徒
Even for Quakers
生活在没有奴隶制的西北地区,
living in the slavery free northwest territory,
这是不可避免的
it was impossible to avoid being drawn into
我们国家历史上最具争议的辩论。
the most contentious debate in the history of our nation.
许多朋友把智慧和创造力结合在一起
Many Friends combined intellect and creativity
克服对他们争取和平与平等工作的反对意见。
to overcome opposition to their work for peace and equality.
Levi 和 Catherine Coffin 就是最好的例子
Levi and Catherine Coffin are prime examples
道德上的独创性。
of such moral ingenuity.
在十九世纪三四十年代,
In the 1830s and 1840s,
印第安纳州韦恩县的纽波特镇,
the town of newport in Wayne county, Indiana,
被认为是最激进的
had a reputation as being one of the most radical
美国的反奴隶制中心。
anti-slavery centers in the United States.
众所周知，数以百计的逃亡奴隶
It was widely known that hundreds of fugitive slaves
经过纽波特;
had passed through newport;
大部分都是通过棺材屋,
most of them through the Coffin home,
他估计,
and he estimated that,
我相信，在他们的一生中
I believe, in the course of their lives
从1826年到1865年，他们帮助了
from 1826 to 1865 they had aided somewhere between
两千三千名逃犯。
two and three thousand fugitives.
据他所知，他们中没有一个人
And to the best of his knowledge none of them
曾经被夺取并重新成为奴隶。
was ever seized and returned to slavery.
Levi Coffin 是个有效的导体
Levi Coffin was an effective conductor
在地下铁路上
on the underground railroad
不仅因为他是个坚定的废奴主义者,
not just because he was a committed abolitionist,
还因为他是一个聪明，坚定的废奴主义者。
but also because he was a smart, committed abolitionist.
他知道如果俘虏奴隶的人入侵纽波特甚至他的家园,
He knew that if slave capturers invaded newport or even his home,
他们有法律的支持。
they would have the force of law behind them.
所以他想尽办法
And so he tried to think of ways
他也许能智取他们。
that he might be able to outwit them.
你可以在房子里看到三个例子。
and you can see three examples of that here at the house.
第一个是井，就在里面。
The first is the well, which is inside.
当然，那样会很方便。
And of course, that would have been convenient.
但它也有一个优势，那就是爱管闲事的邻居
But it also had the advantage that snoopy neighbors who might
没有同情心的人永远不会注意到
not be sympathetic would never be able to notice just how much
棺材里的水都是自己用的
water the coffins were drawing for their own use
或者他们可能带着的18个逃亡的奴隶,
or for the 18 fugitive slaves that they might have with them,
在任何给定的时间。
at any given time.
阁楼上有个藏身之处,
In the attic, there is a hiding place,
如果有必要，人们可以藏在那里。
one where people could have been concealed, if necessary.
他们还有一个假底马车,
they also have a false bottom wagon,
这是另一个有效的方法
which would have been another effective way
运送逃亡的奴隶。
to transport fugitive slaves.
他们会特别危险
They would have been particularly in danger
当他们在公路上的时候。
when they're on the open road.
所以如果你觉得抓奴隶的人可能会跟踪你,
So if you think that slave catchers may be on your trail,
假底旅行车是一个很好的方法
the false bottom wagon is an excellent way
运送一个寻求自由的人。
to transport a freedom seeker.
我认为，对我来说，这是一个很好的例子
I think, to me, it's a good example
将实用性与道德见证相结合。
of combining practicality with a moral witness.
他没有试图躲避警长。
He didn't try and hide from the sheriff.
他只是坦白了
He was just open about it
这才是真正的公民抗命。
and this is what real civil disobedience is about.
公民抗命说这条法律是错误的。
Civil disobedience is saying this law is wrong.
我不会跟着它走的
I am not going to follow it
在人们想抓你的时候抓你。
and doing it out where people can catch you if they want to.
他没有隐瞒自己不仅仅是个指挥家,
He didn't hide the fact that he was, not just a conductor,
在地下铁路上,
on the underground railroad,
当时他被描述为总统
he was described at that time as the president
地下铁路的一部分
of the underground railroad
他被公开这样描述。
and he was described that way publicly.
在他的回忆录里,
In his memoir,
levi Coffin 叙述了一段对话
Levi Coffin recounts a conversation
和一个不赞成的男人
with a man who disapproved
帮助奴隶逃离主人。
of his helping slaves escape from their masters.
我告诉他我小时候读过圣经,
I told him I had read in the bible when I was a boy,
让饥饿的人吃饱穿暖是正确的,
that it was right to feed the hungry and clothe the naked,
并照顾那些堕落于盗贼之中的人
and to minister to those who had fallen among thieves
受了伤,
and were wounded,
而是不分肤色
but that no distinction in regard to color
在圣经中提到过,
was mentioned in the good book,
所以根据它的教导
so in accordance with its teachings
我接待了这些逃犯，并照顾他们。
I had received these fugitives and cared for them.
然后我问: “朋友，我这样做对吗?”
I then asked: "Was I right, friend, in doing so?"
他犹豫不决，似乎不知如何回答。
He hesitated and seemed at a loss how to reply.
我接着说: “你的圣经读起来怎么样？
I continued: "How does thy bible read?
难道不像我说的那样吗?”
Was it not as I have said?"
“是的，他回答说，看起来是这样的。”
"Yes, he answered, it reads somehow so."
他显然想转移话题。
He evidently wished to change the subject.
~ Levi 棺材。
~ Levi Coffin.
除了帮助逃犯逃脱奴役,
In addition to helping fugitives escape from slavery,
棺材和其他废奴主义者试图破坏
Coffin and other abolitionists worked to undermine
它的经济基础,
its economic foundation,
买卖棉花、糖等产品
buying and selling products such as cotton and sugar
种植园雇佣自由劳动者而不是奴隶。
from plantations that hired free laborers instead of using slaves.
1846年，一群废奴主义者
In 1846, a group of abolitionists
决定建立免费劳务批发仓库
decided to establish a free labor wholesale warehouse
敦促 Levi Coffin 监督其运作。
in Cincinnati and urged Levi Coffin to oversee its operation.
春天 Levi 和 Catherine Coffin
in the spring, Levi and Catherine Coffin
从印第安纳州纽波特的家里搬出来
moved from their home in Newport, Indiana
去俄亥俄州的辛辛那提。
to Cincinnati, Ohio.
在辛辛那提的这些年里,
Throughout their years in Cincinnati,
棺材也帮助了那些寻求自由的人
the Coffins also helped those who sought freedom
通过提供教育机会,
by providing opportunities for education,
传授简单的技能，剥夺了那些被奴隶制压迫的人的权利。
teaching simple skills denied those oppressed by slavery.
像 Levi Coffin 这样的人
People like Levi Coffin
不仅给你提供了庇护所
not only provided you with shelter
但却给了你希望。
but then provided you with hope.
帮助黑人学习读写
In helping black people learn to read, write
在联合浸信会教堂的地下室里，那就是自由。
in the basement of union baptist church, that's freedom.
即使他们抓住你，把你带回去
And even if they catch you and take you back
他们不再拥有你了。
they don't own you anymore.
科芬和其他像他一样的人明白，身体上的自由
Coffin and other people like him understood that physical freedom
没有工作，没有办法照顾家人
with no job and no way to take care of your family
只是另一种形式的奴隶制。
is just another form of slavery.
另一个辛辛那提的朋友
Another Cincinnati friend
他们对反对奴隶制的证词特别在意
who took the testimony against slavery particularly to heart
是 Mordecai Morris White。
was mordecai morris white.
他的外祖父是个富有的种植园主,
His maternal grandfather was a wealthy plantation owner,
1846年，当莫里斯 · 怀特只有16岁时,
and in 1846, when Morris White was only 16 years old,
他从祖父那里继承了一大笔遗产,
he inherited a large estate from his grandfather,
包括一些奴隶。
including a number of slaves.
在他二十出头的时候
When he was in his early twenties
作为一个年轻的商人住在辛辛那提,
and living in Cincinnati as a young businessman,
意识到自己是个奴隶主开始困扰他,
the realization that he was a slave owner began to bother him,
所以他骑马旅行
so he made the journey on horseback
一直到北卡罗来纳州,
all the way down to North Carolina,
登记他的奴隶
registered his slaves
确立他的所有权和解放他们的能力,
to establish his ownership and his ability to free them,
然后凌晨三点开始旅行
and then at three in the morning started on a journey
回到中西部。
back to the midwest.
当他到达诺福克时，有人给了他一万美元的黄金
When he got to Norfolk, he was offered $10,000 in gold
为他的奴隶团伙，并拒绝了它。
for his gang of slaves, and turned it down.
个人财产价值
The personal property value
南方六百万奴隶中的一部分更值钱
of the six million slaves in the south was worth more money
比北方所有的工厂和库存都多。
than all the factories and inventory of everything up north.
所以，当你要求把它拿走，送给别人的时候,
And so, when you ask that that be taken away and given away,
那就像告诉宝洁公司
that would be like telling procter & gamble
把他们所有的肥皂都送出去。
to give away all their soap.
我们没有意识到它的价值
We don't realize how much value there was
我们根本不知道那是什么感觉
and we don't have any idea of what it was like
有勇气逃跑。
to have the courage to run away.
最终末底改怀特的小组成功了
Eventually Mordecai White's group made its way
到 Raysville 的贵格会教徒定居点
to Raysville, Indiana, a settlement of Quakers
白人有亲戚的自由有色人种。
and free people of color where white had relatives.
在那里，怀特租了两套房子，并装修了家具
There, White rented and furnished two houses
为他以前的奴隶找工作，为砍柴的人找工作,
for his former slaves, and found jobs for the men chopping wood,
制造围栏和其他工作
making fencing rails, and other employment
让他们能够自给自足。
that would allow them to provide for themselves.
让你的生活说出你所相信的是一种冒险。
It's a risk to let your life speak what you believe.
所以不管你说你相信什么,
So it doesn't matter what you say you believe,
如果你的行为表现出不同的信仰，那就没关系了。
if your actions are showing a different belief, then it doesn't matter.
但这是有风险的。
But it is risky.
没有直接保护
Quakers who did not directly protect
引导奴隶通过地下铁路获得自由
and guide slaves to freedom on the underground railroad
找到了其他的方法，比如辛辛那提的朋友,
found other ways to contribute, such as cincinnati friend,
阿基里斯 · 皮尤和克林顿郡贵格会教徒，艾萨克和莎拉 · 哈维。
achilles pugh and clinton county Quakers, Isaac and Sarah Harvey.
Pugh 拥有一家印刷公司
Pugh owned a printing company
出版了《慈善家》
that published, "The Philanthropist"
是詹姆斯 · 伯尼写的。
that was written by James Birney.
伯尼就像利瓦伊・科芬和来自里普利的约翰・兰金。
Birney was like Levi Coffin and like John Rankin from Ripley.
伯尼是个南方人,
And that Birney was a southerner,
伯尼是肯塔基州丹维尔一个奴隶主的儿子
Birney was the son of a slave owner from Danville, Kentucky
谁说这是不对的。
who said this isn't right.
这就是一个享有特权的人
And so here is a guy of privilege
有很强的道德基础
who has a strong moral base
却对财富视而不见
and just turns his back on wealth
然后开始写论文,
and started writing this paper,
辛辛那提的一些市民烧了他的报纸两次
and some of the citizens of Cincinnati burned his press twice
然后扔到了俄亥俄河里。
and dumped it here in the ohio river.
更糟的是他们决定离开
What's worse they decided to go
阿基里斯・皮尤的家
to achilles pugh's house that night
确保他没有
to make sure that he didn't have
更多的印刷设备。
any more printing equipment handy.
那一定是一段可怕的经历,
And it had to have been a terrifying experience,
让这群愤怒的暴民站在你家门口,
to have this angry mob at your front door step,
你的妻子和孩子都在你家里。
with your wife and your children there in your home.
幸运的是他们没有使用暴力。
Fortunately they didn't commit any violence.
他可以对自己说,
And he could have said to himself,
“这太危险了。
"This is too dangerous.
我不会再这么做了。”
I am not going to do this anymore."
相反，他去了他的印刷机,
Instead he went to his printing press,
把碎片捡起来,
literally picked up the pieces,
继续出版慈善家的作品。
and continuing publishing the philanthropist.
有些人就是典型的例子
There are certain individuals who exemplify
成为贵格会教徒意味着什么,
what it means to be a Quaker,
以及它从一开始就意味着什么,
and what it has meant from the beginning,
其中一个品质就是一定程度的忠诚
and one of the qualities is a degree of faithfulness
去领导，去沟通
to leading, to communicating
或者与上帝沟通，倾听。
or being communicated with God and listening.
Isaac 和 Sarah Harvey 就是一个很好的例子。
And Isaac and Sarah Harvey are a good example of that.
1862年夏末,
In the late summer of 1862,
他正在耕地
he was plowing in his field
你能想象走在马和犁的后面
and can you imagine walking behind horses and a plow
那一定是一种非常沉思的体验，你知道。
and that must be a very meditative kind of experience, you know.
他这么做的时候听到一个声音说,
So he was doing this and he heard a voice that said,
“去华盛顿和总统谈谈”
"Go to washington and talk to the president."
他说，我不..
And he said, I don't --
他不知道声音是在外面还是在里面
he didn't know whether the voice was outside or inside
但他说“我听到了”
but he said, "I hear you."
于是他放下马，照顾他的马,
So he unhitched his horse and took care of his horses,
他回到家里对妻子莎拉说,
went to the house and said to his wife Sarah,
“你愿意和我一起去华盛顿见总统吗?”
"Will you go to washington with me to see the president?"
她用贵格会教徒的方式说: “谁派你来的?”
And she in her Quaker way says, "Who sends thee?"
他说“上帝”
And he says, "The Lord."
所以她当然准备好跟他走了，他们也这么做了。
So of course she's ready to go with him and they do.
内战正在进行
The civil war was underway
整个国家分崩离析,
and the country was divided and devastated,
战争和奴隶制。
by both war and slavery.
但艾萨克 · 哈维相信
But Isaac Harvey was convinced
上帝给了他一个信息让他分享
God had given him a message to share
也许能找到解决办法。
that might provide the solution.
莎拉和艾萨克 · 哈维在华盛顿特区下了火车。
So Sarah and Isaac Harvey get off the train in Washington DC.
他们不了解这个城市;
They don't know the city;
他们对此一无所知。
they don't know anything about it.
他们看着街对面,
They look across the street,
有一个人站在路灯旁边。
and there is a fellow standing over there by a street lamp.
于是他们走过去问他去白宫的路;
So they go over to him and ask directions to the white house;
他们是来见总统的。
they have come to see the president.
所以他问了他们几个问题
So he asks them a few questions
原来他是财政部长,
and it turns out that he is secretary of the treasury,
鲑鱼 P 蔡斯。
Salmon P. Chase.
他来自辛辛那提
He is from Cincinnati;
他曾在几个不同的政治机构任职,
he had served several different political offices,
包括俄亥俄州州长。
including governor of Ohio.
当他发现他们来自威尔明顿
When he finds out they are from Wilmington,
他知道他们是贵格会教徒，他了解这个地区,
and he knows they're Quakers, and he knows the area,
他带着他们，他说，“跟我来，我会让你安顿下来。”
he takes them, he says, "Come with me; I will get you settled."
他把他们带到寄宿公寓之类的地方,
He takes them to a boarding house or something,
给他们找了个房间,
and finds them a room,
他和他们约好了见面时间
and he sets up an appointment with them
去见亚伯拉罕 · 林肯。
to go see Abraham Lincoln.
所以他们去了候诊室
So they went into the waiting room
许多人在读报纸
and many people reading the newspaper
因为安提塔姆之战刚刚被打败
because the battle of antietam had just been fought
北方赢了
and the north had won
但是伤亡惨重。
but there had many, many causalities.
所以他们等待着，认为他们肯定会
So they waited thinking certainly they would probably
永远不要介入这些重要的事情。
never get in with all these important things going on.
但在他们指定的时间，林肯总统召集了他们
But at their appointed time, president Lincoln called them in
他们报告说林肯总统拿起了他的椅子
and they reported that president Lincoln picked up his chair
过来坐在他们中间
and came over and sat between them
这样他就可以和他们私下谈谈。
so that he could talk to them more personally.
他们聊了半个小时
So they talk for about half an hour
在那之后
and at the end of that time
林肯总统签署了一份声明
president Lincoln signed a note
说他们去拜访过他,
saying that they had visited with him,
他们安慰了他，并和他约会。
that they had comforted him and dated it.
我很高兴地宣称
I take pleasure in asserting that I have had
与朋友艾萨克 · 哈维有利可图的性交
profitable intercourse with friend Isaac Harvey
还有他的好妻子莎拉 · 哈维。
and his good wife Sarah Harvey.
愿主安慰他们，就像他们支持我一样。
May the Lord comfort them as they have sustained me.
~ Abraham Lincoln-September 19,1862亚伯拉罕 · 林肯 -1862年9月19日。
~ Abraham Lincoln - September 19, 1862.
哈维来访两天后,
About two days after the Harvey visit,
第一份草稿
the first draft of what would become
解放奴隶宣言交给了国会。
the emancipation proclamation was given to the congress.
在这个初步版本中
In this preliminary version
林肯在他的第二段中提到
Lincoln includes in his second paragraph
几乎和艾萨克 · 哈维的建议一模一样,
almost exactly what Isaac Harvey had suggested,
那就是政府,
and that is that the government,
美国政府从南方购买奴隶。
the US government purchase slaves from the south.
1862年9月22日，林肯发表了如下声明:
On September 22, 1862, Lincoln issued the following:
”这是我的使命,
"That it is my purpose,
在下一次国会会议上
upon the next meeting of congress
再次建议采取切实可行的措施
to again recommend the adoption of a practical measure
对自由接受提供金钱援助
tendering pecuniary aid to the free acceptance
或是否决所有的奴隶制国家，所谓的,
or rejection of all slave states, so called,
那些不会造反的人
the people whereof may not then be in rebellion
反对美国和哪个国家
against the united states and which states
可能会自愿领养,
may then have voluntarily adopted,
或其后可自愿领养,
or thereafter may voluntarily adopt,
立即或逐步废除奴隶制
immediate or gradual abolishment of slavery
在各自的限度内”。
within their respective limits".
还有发生的美妙的事情
And the wonderful thing that happens
当你这么忠诚的时候,
when you are faithful like that,
你有能力做一些事情
is that you are able to do things
你不应该做的事。
you shouldn't be able to do.
你不应该刚到,
You shouldn't be able to just arrive,
在华盛顿特区下车
get off the train in Washington DC
去见林肯总统。
and make your way to see president Lincoln.
当你有这种自信的时候,
And when you have that kind of confidence,
你并不孤单，你可以..。
you are not alone and you can...
你完成了不可思议的事情,
you accomplish incredible things,
还有乔治 · 福克斯的这个想法
and that's along with this idea of George Fox
当他说“让你的生命如此传道”
when he said "Let your life so preach."
换句话说，你的生活，你的所作所为,
In other words, your life will-- what you do,
如果你是忠实的，并调整和聆听
if you are faithful and tuned in and listening
然后付诸行动,
and you act on them,
你的生命会说出你所相信的。
your life will speak what you believe.
所以看到一个人坚守信仰是一个强有力的信息
So it's a powerful message to watch someone live a faith
而不是说出来。
and not just say it.
从17世纪开始
Since the 17th century
贵格会的官方立场是所有的战争和战斗
the official Quaker position has been that all wars and fighting
违背了上帝的旨意
are contrary to the will of God
作为忠诚的基督徒，朋友永远不能携带武器
and that friends as faithful christians, can never bear arms
剥夺人类同胞的生命,
to deprive fellow human beings of their lives,
即使是正当防卫。
even in self-defense.
内战是不同的。
The civil war is different.
他们看到了联盟
They see the confederacy
致力于保卫奴隶制
as committed to the defense of slavery
在贵格会教徒看来,
and that, in Quaker minds,
让它变得绝对不道德，无法辩护。
makes it absolutely immoral, indefensible.
这就是朋友们面临的选择。
So, that's the choice that friends are facing.
如果我们真的接受并相信
If we truly accept and believe that there is indeed
那么我们必须成为一个和平使者。
that of God in every person, then we must be a peacemaker.
我们必须给予每个人充分的正义和平等
We must give full justice and equality to every person
寻求世界所需的和平与正义
and seek the peace and justice that the world needs
灵魂需要我们。
and that the spirit requires of us.
正如国家分裂一样，贵格会也是如此。
Just as the country was divided, so were Quakers.
在对奴隶制的憎恶中挣扎
Torn between their abhorrence of slavery
以及他们和平的见证,
and their testimony of peace,
一些年轻的贵格会教徒加入了联邦军队。
a number of young Quaker men joined the union army.
然而，一个更大的数字,
A larger number, however,
选择不参与暴力;
elected not to participate in violence;
因此他们被贴上懦夫的标签
for this they were labeled as cowards
面对全社会的嘲笑和羞辱。
and faced derision and humiliation by society-at-large.
虽然贵格会教徒不愿意为了他们的原则而杀人,
Although Quakers were not willing to kill for their principles,
他们愿意受苦，甚至愿意为他们而死。
they were willing to suffer, and even die for them.
1864年印第安纳州贵格会教友会纪律
The 1864 Friends discipline for Quakers in Indiana
俄亥俄州西南部也承认了这些挑战
and southwestern Ohio acknowledged the challenges
战争时期的和平证词:
of the peace testimony in wartime:
”如果在他们的一生中,
"If during the common course of their life,
朋友受到攻击，侮辱和迫害,
Friends are attacked, insulted, and persecuted,
他们应该承受错误，不要报复伤害,
they ought to suffer wrong, to revenge no injury,
以德报怨，爱护敌人。
to return good for evil and love their enemies.
还有，如果他们暴露在
So also, should it happen that they are exposed
战争带来的巨大灾难,
to the more extraordinary calamities of war,
他们的行为必须继续遵循同样的原则。
their conduct must continue to be guided by the same principles.
如果侵略者的剑被举起来对抗他们,
If the sword of the invader be lifted up against them,
戒律仍然在手，他们抵抗不邪恶。
the precept is still at hand, that they resist not evil.
如果肉体战士的侮辱和伤害
If the insults and injuries of the carnal warrior
堆积在他们身上,
be heaped upon them,
他们仍然被禁止为自己复仇,
they are still forbidden to avenge themselves,
仍然被命令为迫害他们的人祈祷。
and still commanded to pray for their persecutors.
如果他们被一群敌人包围,
If they are surrounded by a host of enemies,
无论那些敌人多么暴力和恶毒,
however violent and malicious those enemies may be,
基督教的爱必须仍然是不间断的，仍然是普遍的。
christian love must still be unbroken, still universal.
在承受口头攻击的同时
While withstanding verbal
有时是肉体上的迫害,
and sometimes physical persecution,
朋友们找到了在避免暴力的同时提供解决方案的方法。
Friends found ways to contribute solutions while avoiding violence.
比如说，玛丽 · J · 泰勒,
For instance, Mary J. Taylor,
辛辛那提妇女大会的书记员,
clerk of the women's meeting in Cincinnati,
有组织地帮助扎营的士兵
organized assistance for soldiers who were encamped
在加菲尔德公园，她的儿子，威廉・ H ・泰勒博士,
in Garfield Park, and her son, Dr. William H. Taylor,
为伤员提供医疗服务。
provided medical services to the wounded.
其他辛辛那提地区的朋友
Other Cincinnati Area Friends
也面临着采取行动的挑战。
were challenged to action as well.
奋进号，有一条路可以打开,
Endeavor, as way may open,
在某种程度上减轻,
to relieve in some measure,
现在在开罗或附近的有色人种,
the colored people now at or near Cairo,
他们因战争而无家可归
who are without a home in consequence of the war
现在存在于我们热爱的祖国,
now existing in our beloved country,
根据这片土地的法律,
and who, by the laws of the land,
最有可能从奴隶制中解放出来。
are most likely entitled to freedom from slavery...
目前大约有四千人,
at this time there are about 4,000 persons,
主要是妇女和儿童，在那个地方或附近,
principally women and children, at or near that place,
身体健全的人大部分都有工作
the able bodied men being mostly employed
留下他们无助的父亲,
in the opposing armies, leaving their helpless fathers,
没有经济来源的母亲、妻子和孩子。
mothers, wives, and children without the means of support.
1862.
有奴隶
donne: there were slaves
被困在战场中央。
who were caught in the middle of battlegrounds.
所以奴隶们遭受了可怕的苦难
so there was dreadful suffering among the people who were slaves
现在依照法律，自由人,
and were now according to the law, freedmen,
但是他们并没有摆脱痛苦和贫穷等等。
but they were not free from suffering and poverty and so on.
贵格会成立了各种委员会来提供支持
narrator: Quakers formed various committees to provide support
为了那些因战争而受苦受难的人,
for those suffering because of the war,
包括印第安纳州年度会议委员会
including the indiana yearly meeting committee
对有色人种的关注
on the concerns of the people of color
以及违禁品救济委员会,
and the committee for contraband relief,
其中包括来自辛辛那提之友会议的代表,
which included representatives from cincinnati friends meeting,
阿基里斯普和默里米希普利等。
achilles pugh and murray m. shipley, among others.
随着战争接近尾声，接下来的几年,
as the war came to a close and for years to follow,
贵格会教徒也参与其中
Quakers were involved
收拾社会的残局
with picking up the broken pieces of society
并努力重建它。
and working to rebuild it.
根据一些消息来源，在内战期间,
sabrina: according to some sources, during the civil war,
murray Shipley 也参与其中
murray shipley was involved
帮助在南方建立学校
in helping to establish schools in the south
其中包括走下密西西比河
which involved going down the mississippi river,
有时会遭到攻击,
under fire at times,
来自联邦军队或者邦联军队
from either of the union forces or the confederate forces
这样他就可以给那些地区的人们带来救济。
so that he could bring relief to the people in those areas.
多恩: 利维棺材和其他贵格会教徒在辛辛那提地区
donne: levi coffin and other Quakers in the cincinnati area
去了阿拉巴马州和密西西比州
made trips down to alabama and mississippi
看看发生了什么。
to see what was going on.
他们回来，筹集资金
they came back, they raised money and funds
他们成立了西部自由人委员会
and they started this western freedmen's commission
继续获得食物，衣服和补给
to continue to get food and clothing and supplies
救济受苦受难的人们。
and relief for the suffering people.
他们做的第一件事,
one of the first things they did,
除了给奴隶们提供食物和衣服,
besides feed and clothe the slaves,
建立学校并开始教学,
was build schools and start teaching them,
因为他们知道他们会有更好的机会
because they understood that they would have a better chance
在这个新世界中生存，不管它将会是什么,
of surviving in this new world, whatever it was going to be,
为了生存，他们必须
to survive, they were going to have to have
一些基本技能。
some of those basic skills.
内战之后,
carl: after the civil war,
你有450万非洲人后裔,
you had four and a half million people of african descent,
他们中的大多数没有受过正规教育。
most of whom had no formal education.
棺材不仅帮助他们逃跑,
and coffin not only helped them in the process of getting away,
至少2000年，但他后来帮助了一个更大的数字
at least 2000, but he then helped an even a larger number
弗里德曼的机构设立的那种项目:
with the kind of programs that the freedman's bureau set up:
建立学校,
establishment of schools,
建立社会服务体系，让一无所有的人,
establishment of social services that people with nothing,
需要开始成为正式的公民。
needed to begin to become full-fledged citizens.
当棺材在1877年死去的时候,
narrator: when coffin died in 1877,
他的葬礼在辛辛那提的朋友会所举行。
his service was held at cincinnati friends meetinghouse.
八个抬棺人中有四个是被释放的黑人。
four of the eight pallbearers were freed black men.
其中一位演讲者是拉斯特博士牧师,
one of the speakers was rev. dr. rust,
自由人援助协会秘书长
secretary of the freedmen's aid society
美以美会。
of the methodist episcopal church.
Levi 棺材的任务太艰巨了
dr. rust: levi coffin had too great a mission
抽出时间照顾自己,
to spare any time to take care of himself,
上帝照顾了他。
and God took care of him.
他是一个诚实、睿智、明智的人
he was an honest, wise, and judicious man -
明智地选择最实际和明智的方法。
wise in selecting the most practical and judicious methods.
他是个勇敢的人。
he was a brave and courageous man.
到大炮口去就不需要那么大的勇气了
it would take less bravery to go up to the cannon's mouth
而不是做他所做的工作。
than to do the work he did.
当他走过街道的时候,
as he walked through the streets,
他受到群众的嘲笑和威胁。
he was hooted at and threatened by mobs.
战场上没有这样的英雄主义
the battlefield has no such illustrations of heroism
就像他每天展示的那样。
as he exhibited every day.
拉斯特博士牧师1877年。
reverend dr. rust, 1877.
辛辛那提的非裔美国人社区
narrator: the african american community in cincinnati
举办募捐活动为他建造纪念碑,
held fund raisers to build a memorial for him,
但保持简洁是贵格会的惯例
but it was Quaker practice to maintain simplicity
甚至在死亡中也是平等的。
and equality even in death.
按照他的意愿,
in accordance with his wishes,
catherine 棺材埋葬了她的丈夫
catherine coffin had her husband buried
在会议墓地的一个无名坟墓里。
in an unmarked grave in the meetings cemetery.
1881年凯瑟琳・克里夫去世时,
when catherine coffin died in 1881,
她也被埋在一个没有标记的坟墓里
she was also buried in an unmarked grave
在朋友墓地。
in the friends cemetery.
20年后的1901年，辛辛那提的朋友们聚会
twenty years later, in 1901, cincinnati friends meeting
被告知「非本会会员
was informed that "persons not in membership with us
”想为已故的利瓦伊人的棺材立一座纪念碑
"desire to erect a monument to the late levi coffin
在 Spring Grove 公墓的停车场”
on our lot in spring grove cemetery."
辛辛那提的朋友会议批准了
cincinnati friends meeting granted permission
竖立一座纪念碑
to erect a monument
只要朋友们认可这个题词。
so long as friends approved of the inscription.
在几个简单的墓碑之间，在贵格会的一部分
among a few simple headstones in the Quaker section
在 Spring Grove 公墓，有一个六英尺高的标记,
of spring grove cemetery, stands a single six-foot marker,
在1902年5月30日的一个仪式上。
dedicated in a ceremony on may 30, 1902.
纪念碑上刻有以下字句:
inscribed on the monument are the following words:
女贵格会教徒2: 利瓦伊棺材，死于1877年9月16日
female Quaker 2: levi coffin, died 9th mo. 16, 1877
在他79岁的时候，一个基督教慈善家。
in his 79th year, a christian philanthropist.
1881年5月22日，凯瑟琳 · 棺材逝世，享年78岁,
catherine coffin died 5th mo 22,
1881 in her 78th year,
她的工作做得很好。
her work well done.
高尚的捐助者帮助成千上万的人获得自由
noble benefactors aiding thousands to gain freedom -
来自辛辛那提有色人种的致敬。
a tribute from the colored people of cincinnati.
[音乐]
[music]
内战结束后，另一个组织
narrator: after the civil war, another group that garnered
贵格会教徒的关注和同情
the attention and sympathies of Quakers
美洲原住民
were native americans,
特别是夏安族，威奇托族和科曼奇族。
specifically, the cheyenne, wichita and comanche tribes.
美国历史上最具讽刺意味的事情之一
thomas: one of the delicious ironies of american history
是不是当将军的尤利西斯·辛普森·格兰特
was that when general ulysses s. grant
1869年成为总统,
became president in 1869,
他决定美国政府
he decided that the u.s. government
需要一个新的印度政策。
needed a new indian policy.
一个强调和平的国家。
one that emphasized peace.
接管印第安事务的人
one that took the administration of indian affairs
远离军队
away from the army
以及经常腐败的私人承包商和代理商,
and private contractors and agents who were often corrupt,
然后交给了教堂。
and turned it over to the churches.
那些可能是人道主义者的人。
people who presumably would be humanitarian.
他们愿意在地球上实践和平，对人类怀有善意。
who would practice peace on earth, good will toward men.
1869年，一群贵格会教徒
narrator: in 1869, when a group of Quakers went to see
总统选举 Grant 并提出建议
president elect grant and made the suggestion
不是士兵作为印度特工,
that instead of soldiers as indian agents,
任命有信仰的人,
people of faith be appointed,
格兰特认真地听着贵格会教徒的话，回答道:
grant listened attentively to the Quakers, and responded:
先生们，你们的建议很好。
president grant: gentlemen, your advice is good.
我接受。
I accept it.
现在给我一些印度特工朋友的名字
now give me the names of some friends for indian agents
我会任命他们。
and I will appoint them.
如果你能把印第安人变成贵格会教徒的话
if you can make Quakers out of the indians
这样他们就不会反抗了。
it will take the fight out of them.
让我们和平共处。
let us have peace.
尤利西斯·辛普森·格兰特。
ulysses s. grant.
旁白: 因此，总统尤利西斯·辛普森·格兰特
narrator: thus, president ulysses s. grant
被引导去实行后来被称为“贵格会政策”
was led to pursue what became known as the "Quaker policy,"
朋友和其他神职人员的任命
the appointment of friends and other clergy
监督腐败横行的美国印第安事务局,
to oversee the corruption-ridden bureau of u.s. indian affairs,
在全国各地充当“印度特工”
and to act as "indian agents"
across the country,
分配资金和物资
distributing funds and supplies
部落失去了越来越多的土地
to tribes who were losing more and more of their land
来自东方的定居者,
to settlers from the east,
被迫住在保留地。
and being forced to live on reservations.
人们相信，大部分的动机
it is believed that much of the motivation
是因为他们的正面声誉
for involving the Quakers was their positive reputation
在美洲原住民社区。
among native american communities.
William Penn 先开始的。
mary: now, william penn started that.
当他来到宾夕法尼亚州,
when he came to pennsylvania,
他和印第安人签订了条约。
he made treaties with the indians.
这些条约没有被破坏。
these treaties were not broken.
他们购买了土地,
they purchased land,
他们尽可能地诚实
they tried to be as honest as they could
对印第安人一视同仁。
and as equal and fair to the native-americans.
所以，这个传统是通过社会传承下来的。
so, that tradition was handed down through the society.
他们建造学校，帮助他们建造磨坊
and they built schools, helped them build mills
提供东西
and provided things
这样印第安人就可以建立自己的家园
so that the native-americans could establish their own homes
为自己创造生活。
and make a life for themselves.
旁白: 再一次，许多涉及
narrator: once again, many of those involved
来自中西部。
in the effort, came from the midwest.
辛辛那提的朋友 Murray Shipley 担任主席
cincinnati friend murray shipley served as chairman
联合执行委员会的朋友
of the associated executive committee of friends
印度事务,
on indian affairs,
辛辛那提会议的其他成员也被任命
and other members of cincinnati meeting were appointed
作为印度特工包括不屈不挠的哈里特公牛,
as indian agents including the indomitable harriet steer,
他在密苏里州的部落待了几个月,
who spent several months with tribes in missouri,
还有阿基里斯・皮尤他去过堪萨斯州和俄克拉何马领地
and achilles pugh, who traveled to kansas and oklahoma territory
和另外两个朋友在联合执行委员会。
with two other friends on the associated executive committee.
最初，贵格会似乎得到了支持
initially, Quakers seemed to have the support
普通大众对平原部落的工作。
of the general public in their work with the plains tribes.
辛辛那提商业论坛报报道:
the cincinnati commercial tribune reported:
新闻记者: 贵格会代理人不知疲倦
newspaper reporter: the Quaker agents are unwearied
他们努力改善
in their efforts for the amelioration
印第安人的情况,
of the indians' condition,
并且诚实地分发配给
and honest in dispensing the rations
以及他们有权获得的年金。
and annuities they are entitled to receive.
在旧制度下，特工很少和部落住在一起,
under the old system, the agents seldom lived with the tribes,
而新的代理人则与他们同在;
while the new agents abide with them;
这是一个很大的优势。
and this is a great advantage.
辛辛那提商业论坛1869年9月23日。
cincinnati commercial tribune september 23, 1869.
然而，许多西方定居者
narrator: however, many western settlers
不喜欢这个实验。
were not fans of the experiment.
托马斯: 他们中的许多人是学校的:
thomas: many of them were of the school:
唯一的好印第安人就是死掉的印第安人。
the only good indian is a dead indian.
当他们看到贵格会教徒来主张正义
when they saw Quakers coming in urging justice
美洲原住民
for native americans,
指出地方官员,
pointing out how very often local officials,
白人定居者偷美洲原住民
white settlers, were stealing from native americans,
侵占他们的土地,
encroaching on their lands,
扣押本应属于他们的政府资金,
withholding government funds that were rightly theirs,
这并没有让那些人喜欢贵格会教徒。
this did not endear Quakers to those people.
很快，华盛顿就被投诉淹没了
so soon, washington was being inundated by complaints
贵格会教徒是完全不现实的
from settlers that the Quakers were completely unrealistic
他们正在危及移民的生命。
and that they were endangering the lives of settlers.
不幸的是，对贵格会的信任
narrator: unfortunately, the trust placed in the Quakers
格兰特总统的意见并没有得到官员们的认同
by president grant was not shared by officials
在拉瑟福德·伯查德·海斯管理方面。
in the administration of rutherford b. hayes.
1879年，遭遇敌对
in 1879, encountering antagonism
缺乏政府官员的合作,
and lack of cooperation by government officials,
贵格会教徒退出了政府资助的工作
Quakers withdrew from government sponsored work
而是将他们的努力
and instead directed their efforts
建立贵格会议,
toward establishing Quaker meetings,
在保留地上建造学校和为学校配备人员,
building and staffing schools on reservations,
以及维持至今仍在继续的关系。
and maintaining relationships that continue today.
[音乐]
[music]
旁白: 在1896年，当有战争的谣言
narrator: in 1896, when there were rumors of war
美国和大不列颠之间的战争，默里・希普利,
between the united states and great britain, murray shipley,
在辛辛那提朋友会议上的三个牧师之一,
one of three recorded ministers at cincinnati friends meeting,
还有威廉・ H ・泰勒和安娜・ M ・约翰逊,
along with william h. taylor and anna m. johnson,
认为它提供了:
thought it provided:
这是一个很好的机会来宣布
murray: a great opportunity to proclaim
我们社会反对一切战争的原则,
the principles of our society in opposition to all war,
以及我们倡导的和平手段
and our advocacy of peaceful means
调整所有国际困难。
of adjusting all international difficulties.
Murray Shipley 1896年。
murray shipley, 1896.
旁白: 他补充说，朋友的目的是:
narrator: and he added that the aim of the friends was:
不是翻译基督的教导
murray: not to translate christ's teachings
成为适应当时习俗的自由渲染,
into a free rendering adapted to the customs of the day,
而是维护他的标准
but to uphold his standard
让世界不仅反对奴隶制，而且反对战争。
and let the world become not only anti-slavery, but anti-war.
这种乐观的19世纪希望是短暂的。
narrator: this optimistic 19th century hope was short lived.
相反，在下个世纪，到处都是贵格会教徒
instead, in the next century, Quakers everywhere
发现自己不断受到挑战
found themselves repeatedly challenged
维护和平证词
to uphold the peace testimony
以平等、真理和简单为基础。
with its underpinnings of equality, truth and simplicity.
战争于1914年在英国首先爆发。
paul: war breaks out in 1914 in england first.
有一个问题，因为在英国的朋友,
there's a problem because friends in england,
英国的贵格会教徒清楚地知道他们是和平主义者。
Quakers in england are clear that they are pacifists.
他们在英国所做的就是建立
what they do in england is to establish
朋友救护车服务，那是一个医疗团,
the friends ambulance service, which was a medical corps,
独立于军队之外。
independent of the army.
年轻人，主要是公谊会教徒，但不仅限于公谊会教徒,
young men, principally Quakers but not exclusively Quakers,
志愿开救护车的人
who would volunteer to drive ambulances
在前线当医护兵。
and serve as medics at the front.
Rufus Jones James Babbitt 和 Henry Cadbury
donne: so rufus jones and james babbitt and henry cadbury
和当时其他一些贵格会领袖,
and some other Quaker leaders at the time,
决定他们需要一个类似的组织
decided that they needed a similar organization
这样他们就能做点什么,
for american Quakers so that they could do something,
这样他们就可以服役而不用像军队那样服役。
so they could serve without serving in the military's way.
那是在1917年,
narrator: it was then, in 1917,
美国朋友服务委员会,
that the american friends service committee, or afsc,
形成了，用来吃饭，穿衣,
was formed, to feed, clothe,
为战争受害者提供援助。
and provide aid to the victims of war.
如果你看看制服
ruth: if you look at the uniforms
他们看起来和制服一模一样
they looked exactly like the uniforms
美国军队在那次冲突中所穿的,
that the american military were wearing in that conflict,
那是因为他们实际上是在购买
and that was because they were actually buying
多余的军装,
surplus army uniforms,
让这些年轻人穿上这个。
and outfitting these young men in this.
所以当你看到他们袖子上的制服
so when you see the uniforms they have on the sleeve
红色和黑色的星星，这是采用作为标志
the red and black star, which was adopted as the logo
为美国朋友服务委员会工作。
for the american friend service committee.
还有很多年轻的贵格会教徒
donne: and there were lot of young Quakers
和其他和平教会的成员，比如门诺派教徒
and other members of peace churches like the mennonite
还有那些不想去打仗的弟兄们的教堂。
and the church of the brethren who did not want to go fight.
他们愿意服役，他们愿意牺牲,
they were willing to serve, they were willing to die,
但他们没有，他们不能杀人。
but they didn't, they couldn't kill.
所以当法国还有炸弹落下的时候,
so while there were bombs still falling in france,
美国贵格会和英国贵格会
american Quakers and british Quakers
正在重建农舍
were rebuilding farmhouses
帮助那些整个城镇都被摧毁的人们。
and helping the people whose whole towns had been destroyed.
贵格会教徒进去重建家园,
Quakers went in there and were rebuilding,
即使破坏仍在发生。
even as the destruction was still happening.
那些忠诚的成员之一
narrator: one of those devoted members
美国朋友服务委员会的成员
of the american friends service committee
是俄亥俄州 Wilmington 市人 Luther Warren。
was wilmington, ohio native, luther warren.
Luther Warren 讲述了一个震撼人心的故事
ruth: luther warren tells this amazing powerful story
和这个法国家庭共度一天
about spending the day with this french family
此时此刻，这个家族仅剩的一切
and at this point, all that is left of this family
是奶奶，妈妈和一个小女孩,
is grandma, mom, and a little girl,
所以卢瑟和他的几个合伙人
and so luther and a couple of his partners
一起为这个家庭建造这个家。
are working together to build this home for this family.
他们很感激有这个家,
they are so grateful to have this home,
让他们有地方住。
to have a roof over their heads again.
卢瑟和他的人回营地去了
luther and the men leave to go back to their camp
明天一早就知道
and find out first thing in the morning
战线已经转移
that the battle lines have shifted
所以他们必须回到同一个家庭
and so they have to go back to this same family
把他们从他们刚建的房子里赶出去。
and evacuate them from this home that they just built.
这个故事真正让人惊叹的是卢瑟 · 沃伦,
what's really amazing about this story is luther warren,
maynard McKay Mark McMillan
maynard mckay, mark mcmillan
这里所有的年轻人
all of these young men from this area
首先，他们有这些文化体验
they're having, first of all, these cultural experiences
俄亥俄州西南部的农场男孩
that farm boys from southwest ohio
从来没有过。
have never had before.
但想想这需要多大的勇气,
but to think about the courage that it took,
说“不，我不相信那是什么东西”
to say "no, I don't believe that that is something
”我可以参与其中
"that I can participate in
因此，我将选择这么做。”
and so this is what I am going to choose to do instead."
然后才知道他们也处于同样的危险之中
and then to know that they were in just as much danger
那个拿着步枪的年轻人。
as the young man who were carrying rifles.
有些人是医护人员
neil: some of them worked as medics
或者在医院里，或者在其他地方,
or in the hospitals, that and other functions,
而是医院的工作，这在难民工作中很常见
but hospital work, and this was common to work with refugees
孩子和年轻母亲,
and children and young mothers,
专注于那种解脱。
a kind of focus on that kind of relief.
我喜欢这样的组合: 尝试做出改变
I like this combination: trying to make changes
将产生长期和广泛的影响
that will have long term and broad effects
美国朋友服务委员会已经这么做了。
the american friend service committee has done that.
根据华莱士 · T · 科莱特的说法,
narrator: according to wallace t. collett,
他是主席
who served as chairman
在1970年代的美国朋友服务委员会,
of the american friends service committee in the 1970s,
1917年的组织者
its organizers in 1917
受到 William Penn 的一句名言的启发:
were inspired by a quotation from william penn:
那就让我们试试爱的力量
william: let us then try what love will do;
因为如果男人看到我们爱他们,
for if men did once see we love them,
我们很快就会发现他们不会伤害我们。
we should soon find they would not harm us.
尽管大战在1918年结束,
narrator: though the great war came to a close in 1918,
美国朋友服务委员会的工作仍在继续。
the work of the american friends service committee continued.
每天大约有一百万个孩子
ruth: something close to a million children a day
很多年来,
for a number of years,
在欧洲的救援工作。
were being fed by this relief work in europe.
这项工作有一个强大的遗产
that work had a powerful legacy
因为他们不仅喂养法国孩子,
because they weren't just feeding french children,
他们也在喂养德国的孩子。
they were feeding german children as well.
他们喂养任何需要被喂养的人。
they were feeding anyone who needed to be fed.
有一个叫乔 · 沃克的人,
there is a man named joe volk, who, for a number of years,
是执行秘书
was the executive secretary
朋友的国家立法委员会。
of the friend's committee on national legislation.
二十世纪七八十年代他在德国旅行,
in the 1970s and 1980s he was traveling in germany,
他们在研究东西方关系
and they were working on east-west relations
和反核武器工作,
and anti-nuclear weapons work,
但是他正在和一些官员谈话
but he was talking with some officials
德国政府的高层。
high up in the german government.
在某种程度上，我个人对此感到非常惊讶
and at some point was just kind of really personally amazed
这些人是如此的愿意和开放
that these people were so willing and open
和他谈谈,
to talk with him,
当他们不愿意和别人交谈的时候
when they weren't willing and open to talk with other people
最后他问了一个人，这是什么？
and so he finally asked somebody, what is it?
why me?
why us?
为什么是美国朋友服务委员会？
why the american friend service committee?
为什么你和我们说话，却不和其他人说话？
why are you talking to us and you wont talk to anyone else?
这个德国官员说，因为我不会在这里
and this german official said because I wouldn't be here
如果你没有喂饱我的父母。
if you hadn't fed my parents.
所以我们说的是一代人之后，对吧,
and so we are talking about a generation after, right,
这家伙的父母是贵格会教徒养大的
this guy's parents had been fed by Quakers
在第一次世界大战后的几年里。
in the years after world war i.
所以我们想了很多，听了很多关于涟漪效应的事
so we think a lot and we hear a lot about the ripple effects
冲突结束后的冲突,
of conflict after the conflict is over,
而是考虑人道主义援助的涟漪效应
but to think about the ripple effects of humanitarian aid
以及几代人之后的和平工作
and of peace work generations after that's happened
我觉得这个故事讲得不够多。
and I think that's a story that doesn't get told enough.
[音乐]
[music]
到了1940年，很明显，另一个主要的冲突
narrator: by 1940, it was clear that another major conflict
正在欧洲酝酿。
was brewing in europe.
罗伯特 · 琼斯，辛辛那提朋友会部长,
robert jones, minister of cincinnati friends meeting,
参加了印第安纳州里士满的一个聚会,
attended a gathering in richmond, indiana,
正如他们所解释的,
"for the purpose of,"
as they explained,
“讨论在这个混乱的世界里朋友能做些什么”
"discussing what friends can do in this world of confusion."
他报告说美国朋友服务委员会
he reported that the american friends service committee
试图与政府合作,
was trying to work out, with the government,
为依良心拒服兵役者提供某种服务,
some sort of service for the conscientious objectors,
如果战争来临。
should war come.
其结果是“选择性培训和服务法案,
the result was "the selective training and service act,
其中包括豁免任何人参加战斗,
which, included an exemption from combat for any person "who,
因为宗教训练和信仰,
"by reason of religious training and belief,
”是出于良心反对的
"is conscientiously opposed
参与任何形式的战争”
to participation in war in any form."
第二次世界大战期间,
thomas: during world war ii,
联邦法律限制了替代性服务
federal law restricted the alternative service
出于良心拒服兵役者
of conscientious objectors
美国境内的项目。
to projects within the united states.
所以你看到了出于良心拒服兵役者
so you saw conscientious objectors
他们在精神病院做护理员,
who worked as attendants in mental hospitals,
他们在林业营地工作
who worked in forestry camps
从事保护或灭火工作。
doing conservation or fire-fighting work.
一些最勇敢的依良心拒服兵役者
some of the bravest conscientious objectors
自愿做医学实验的小白鼠,
volunteered to be guinea pigs in medical experiments,
检测各种疾病的疫苗
testing vaccines for various diseases
甚至参加饥饿实验
or even taking part in starvation experiments
目的是为了更好地理解
that were aimed at getting a better understanding
前战俘们
of how former pows
或者集中营的幸存者可以通过护理恢复健康。
or concentration camp survivors could be nursed back to health.
所以他们有自己的勇气。
so they were brave in their own way.
几个来自中西部的贵格会教徒
narrator: several Quakers from the midwest
参加了这些危险的实验。
took part in these dangerous experiments.
Wayne Overmeyer
donne: wayne overmeyer
作为实验对象参与实验
participated as human guinea pigs
在这些实验中
in some of these experiments
在第二次世界大战中。
in world war ii.
David Stoffregen 是第一个在辛辛那提注册的贵格会教徒
david stoffregen was the first Quaker in cincinnati to register
作为那场战争的联合指挥官，并加入 CPS 集中营。
as a co for that war and to sign up for the cps camps.
旁白: 另一个年轻的贵格会教徒 T。坎比琼斯,
narrator: another young Quaker by the name of t. canby jones,
也是二战期间的狱警。
was also a co during world war ii.
Canby 是个非常非常有趣的家伙,
neil: canby is very, very interesting fellow,
耶鲁大学的博士学位。
a phd from yale.
他是个出于良心拒服兵役者，和狱警一起工作
he was a conscientious objector and worked with the cos
以及美国的一些地方
in norway as well as some places here in the united states
他也是个圣经学家。
and he's also a biblical scholar.
他出生在日本，他的父亲是一个传教士。
he was born in japan, his father was a missionary.
他的父亲成为校长或校长
his father became the principal or president
他在南方的一所黑人大学长大
of a black university in the south where he was raised
所以他总是在许多不同的方面走在最前沿。
so he's always been on cutting edge in many different ways.
坎比后来成为了一位受人爱戴的教授
narrator: canby later became a beloved professor
俄亥俄州威明顿学院的和平活动家,
and peace activist at wilmington college in ohio,
他在学校里被称为“贵格会先生”
where he was known on campus as "mr. Quaker."
禁止向战区派遣救援人员
barred from sending relief workers to battle zones
二战期间,
during wwii,
一个战时的顾虑
one wartime concern
美国朋友服务委员会致辞
the american friends service committee addressed
是超过
was the plight of more than
12万日裔美国人因涉嫌
120,000 japanese americans arrested on the suspicion
成为“敌对外星人”
of being "enemy aliens"
在1941年珍珠港遭到袭击之后。
after pearl harbor was attacked in 1941.
全家都被关在临时拘留营里,
entire families were imprisoned in temporary internment camps,
直到他们可以从西海岸“重新安置”
until they could be "relocated"
from the west coast
被新成立的 WRA 或“战争重新安置当局”
by the newly created wra or "war relocation authority."
在珍珠港爆炸后48小时内
sabrina: within 48 hours of the bombing of pearl harbor
罗斯福总统发布了一项行政命令,
president roosevelt issued an executive order,
基本上围捕了数百名日裔美国人
that basically rounded up hundreds of japanese americans
他们住在西海岸，把他们关进拘留营
that lived on the west coast, and put them in internment camps
确认他们是敌方外星人。
identifying them as enemy aliens.
他们不得不卖掉农田,
they had to sell their farmlands,
关闭他们的生意,
close their businesses,
他们去了这些集中营
and they went to these camps
只有他们能带的东西。
literally with only what they could carry.
他们被告知必须呆在那里,
they were told that that they had to stay there,
直到军事命令解除,
until the military order was lifted,
或撤销，或修改。
or rescinded, or modified.
雷蒙德 · 布斯曾是贵格会的牧师,
g. raymond booth was a former Quaker pastor,
曾任太平洋海岸执行秘书
and had been a former executive secretary of the pacific coast
美国朋友服务委员会部门。
division of american friends service committee.
他是 WRA 在辛辛那提的第一位代表
he was the first representative of the wra here in cincinnati
会见了辛辛那提的朋友们,
and met with members of cincinnati friends meeting,
讨论他的担忧
to discuss his concerns
帮助日裔美国人安顿下来。
for helping japanese americans get settled.
作为回应，一家青年旅社建立了
narrator: in response, a hostel was established--
临时住所，日裔美国人
temporary quarters-- where japanese americans
可以待到就业
could stay until employment
可以找到更长久的生活安排。
and more permanent living arrangements could be found.
辛辛纳提大学宿舍
a university of cincinnati dormitory
被租用作旅馆。
was leased for use as the hostel.
布斯以身作则,
and booth led by example,
雇佣第一个集中营成员
hiring the first internment camp member
搬到辛辛那提，他的秘书 Elva Shinozaki。
to relocate to cincinnati, his secretary, elva shinozaki.
辛辛那提的朋友们都参与其中,
sabrina: cincinnati friends were greatly involved in this,
他们会一起野餐
they would coordinate picnics
和年轻的日裔美国人在一起。
with the young japanese americans.
他们邀请他们来做礼拜
they invited them to come to worship
以及大约700人
and about 700 individuals
利用宿舍提供的服务。
took advantage of the services offered through the hostel.
住在那里的几个人觉得很受欢迎
several people who lived there felt welcomed enough
辛辛那提的朋友说他们刚决定参加会议
by cincinnati friends that they just decided to join the meeting
成为贵格会教徒。
to become Quakers themselves.
旅馆关门后,
narrator: after the hostel closed,
辛辛那提贵格会继续他们的关系
cincinnati Quakers continued their relationship
和日本人,
with the japanese,
捐款在日本重建一所朋友学校
contributing funds to rebuild a friends school in japan
已经被炸弹摧毁了。
which had been destroyed by bombs.
与此同时，正如它在 wwi 之后,
meanwhile, as it had after wwi,
二战结束时，美国朋友服务委员会
at the end of wwii the american friends service committee
派遣救援人员帮助重建欧洲。
sent relief workers to help rebuild europe.
一个年轻的贵格会教徒加入了这个行列，他就是罗伯特 · “鲍勃”· 麦考伊
one young Quaker who joined that effort was robert "bob" mccoy
他在俄亥俄州西南部的一个农场长大。
who grew up on a farm in southwestern ohio.
然后美国朋友服务委员会
donne: then american friends service committee went over
回到饱受战争蹂躏的欧洲，开始工作
to war-torn europe and began doing the work
为当时在场的饥民提供食物,
of feeding the starving people who were there,
德国人，奥地利人和俄罗斯人。
both german and austrian and russian.
我是说，他们不仅仅是去喂饱盟友的孩子,
I mean, they didn't just go feed the children of allies,
但他们养活了敌人的孩子。
but they fed the children of the enemies.
鲍勃 · 麦考伊战后在那里工作了四年。
and bob mccoy worked there for about four years after the war.
有一天，我在外面开卡车的时候,
narrator: one day, while out driving a truck,
鲍勃的工作伙伴有一段难忘的经历
bob's work partner had quite a memorable experience
和一个当地村民。
with a local villager.
他从一个村庄走到另一个村庄,
donne: as he went along from village to village,
如果有人在走路，他就会停下来接他
he would stop and pick up people if they were walking
看起来他还有地方,
and it looked like he had room,
所以他抱起了这个老人,
and so he picked up this elderly man,
载他去了下一个村庄,
gave him a ride to the next village,
老人从卡车旁边走进来问道,
and the old man came in on the side of the truck and asked,
“我欠你多少钱?”
"how much do I owe you?"
还有那个美国朋友服务委员会的家伙
and the guy, the american friends service committee fellow
说: “没什么，这是我们的工作;
said "nothing, this is what we do;
你知道，我们是来帮忙的。”
you know, we are here to help."
老人抬头一看，看到了贵格会的徽章,
and the old man glanced up and he saw the Quakers insignia,
他说，“啊，贵格会教徒，这就解释了一切。”
and he said, "ah, Quakers, that explains everything."
是因为
that was left over because
他们记得贵格会在一战中的所作所为。
they remembered what Quakers had done in world war i.
这让我想起了 William Penn 的一句话,
and that makes me think about that saying from william penn,
“让我们尝试爱的力量”
"let us then try what love will do,"
我认为爱是在一战期间和战后自由给予的
and I think love given freely during and after world war i
在50年和60年后被人们记住
was remembered 50
and 60 years later
并在50或60年后对你的敌人产生影响。
and had an impact 50 or 60 years later on your enemies.
我的意思是，这是一个非常有力的教训,
I mean that's such a powerful lesson,
它给基督教的教义以信任和分量
and it gives credence and weight to the teachings of christianity
还有贵格会。
and of Quakerism.
保罗: 战后，为了认识到这一点,
paul: after the war in recognition of this,
英国朋友服务委员会
friends service committee in england
还有美国朋友服务委员会
and the american friends service committee
被授予诺贝尔和平奖。
are awarded a nobel peace prize.
这是国际社会对战争替代品的认可,
it's international recognition of the alternative to warfare,
贵格会教徒最好的代表。
that Quakers in their best sense, represent.
[音乐]
[music]
在接下来的三十年里
narrator: over the next three decades
美国人的社会和政治焦点
the social and political focus of americans
以及世界上大部分地区,
and much of the world,
从欧洲转移到日益壮大的民权运动
shifted from europe to the growing civil rights movement
在美国境内。
within the united states.
1954年，俄亥俄州 Hillsboro 的五位黑人父母
in 1954, five black parents in hillsboro, ohio
对当地的学校董事会提起了诉讼
brought a lawsuit against the local school board
学校实行种族隔离政策。
for its policy of segregation in the schools.
布朗诉教育委员会一案的裁决
in its ruling on brown vs. the board of education
那年早些时候，美国最高法院
earlier that year, the u.s. supreme court had
废除了“分开但平等”的规则
"abolished the 'separate but equal' rule under which
希尔斯伯勒的非裔美国儿童
"hillsboro's african american children had been educated
在种族隔离的学校里待了几十年。”
in segregated schools for decades."
全国有色人种协进会在 Hillsboro 的诉讼中，提供了法律咨询。
the naacp helped provide legal counsel in the hillsboro suit.
瑟古德·马歇尔成功辩护
"thurgood marshall, who successfully argued
“棕色的箱子，写了摘要，签了请愿书”
"the brown case, wrote the briefs and signed the petition
提交给辛辛那提地方法院”
submitted to the district court in cincinnati."
父母之一，伊莫金 · 柯蒂斯,
one of the parents, imogene curtis,
参加当地的贵格会会议
approached local Quaker meetings
在利斯堡和威明顿附近,
in nearby leesburg and wilmington,
请求他们的帮助。
and requested their help.
这就是俄亥俄州希尔斯伯勒的自由学校,
this was how the freedom schools of hillsboro, ohio,
也被称为“厨房学校”开始。
also known as the
"kitchen schools" began.
Rebecca Godfrey 的母亲参与了这次行动。
rebecca Godfrey's mother was involved with the effort.
我爸爸刚好在服务
rebecca: my dad happened to be serving
当时在一个委员会参加年度会议
on a committee at the time for the yearly meeting
收到请求的人。
that received the request.
他回到家告诉了她
he came home and he informed her
他自愿让她每周去一次希尔斯伯勒
that he had volunteered her to go to hillsboro once a week
帮助这些孩子上学。
and help with the schooling of these children.
所以贵格会教师团体
so the group of Quaker teachers--
他们有四个人
there were four of them--
每周一都会去希尔斯伯勒,
would go to hillsboro on mondays,
在那天和孩子们见面，一起工作。
and meet, and work with the children on that day.
然后，他们会留下教学计划
and then, they would leave lesson plans
为母亲教师执行
for the mother teachers to carry out
这周剩下的时间。
for the rest of the week.
这就是为什么他们被称为厨房学校
and that's how they became known as the kitchen schools
因为他们中的很多人,
because a lot of them,
他们围着一张餐桌坐了四五个孩子。
they sat around a kitchen table four or five children.
在此期间，终身的纽带建立了
narrator: during that, lifelong bonds were established
黑人父母和贵格会教师之间的关系。
between the black parents and the Quaker teachers.
我和我十几岁的儿子在家庭聚会
rebecca: I was at a family reunion with my teenage son
他邀请了他的朋友来。
who invited his friend to come.
他的朋友是混血儿
and his friend is biracial
我说“你在 Hillsboro 有亲戚吗?”
and I said, "do you have any relations in hillsboro?"
然后他说“我想是的”。
and he goes "i think so.
我想我的...”
I think my--"
我说“伊莫金和奥维尔 · 柯蒂斯，有可能吗?”
I said, "imogene and orville curtis, by any chance?"
他说”我爸爸是 Orville Curtis
and he says, "well, my dad was orville curtis
他以他叔叔的名字命名。
"and he was named after his uncle.
我想他们住在希尔斯伯勒。
I think that they lived in hillsboro".
所以，在这里，你知道，我妈妈和伊莫金女士一起工作
and so, here, you know, my mom had worked with ms. imogene
在厨房学校和两代以后
in the kitchen schools and two generations later
她的孙子和奥维尔・柯蒂斯,
her grandson and orville curtis,
她丈夫的侄孙是最好的朋友。
her husband's great nephew are best friends.
你知道，这让你有点自豪
you know, it makes you kind of proud
你妈妈也参与其中。
that your mom had a part in that.
[音乐]
[music]
当美国卷入冲突
narrator: when american involvement in the conflict
东南亚局势升级，贵格会的担忧也随之升级。
in southeast asia escalated, so did Quaker concern.
世界各地的朋友都抗议战争。
friends everywhere protested the war.
威明顿学院,
wilmington college,
在贵格会会长的领导下,
under the leadership of Quaker presidents,
成为贵格会激进主义的焦点。
became a focus of Quaker activism.
Gary Kersey 威明顿学院的毕业生,
gary kersey, a graduate of wilmington college,
叙述他在学校的时光
recounts his time at the school
在示威高峰期。
during the peak of demonstrations.
我看到这些示威游行开始展开。
gary: I saw these demonstrations starting to unfold.
我记得有人反对战争
I remember there were those who opposed the war
在人行道的一边排队
kind of lining up on one side of the sidewalk
还有那些支持军队的人
and those who were in support of the troops
在另一边。
were on the other side.
我心想,
and I thought to myself,
我可以从大学礼堂的后楼梯下去,
you know, I can go back down the back stairs of college hall,
坐上我的美洲狮去 Hardy’s
get in my cougar and go to hardy's
避免这种两难困境
and avoid this whole dilemma
我是否会参与其中,
as to whether i'm going to be a part of this,
我是否会参加战争
whether i'm going to be for the war
或者我们可以说是反对战争。
or shall we say against the war.
我必须说，我认为我已经达到了我生命中的一个点
and I must say that I think I had reached the point in my life
that up 'till that time,
几乎每个人都在告诉我应该做什么
most everybody had been telling me what I ought to do
我应该说什么，我应该有什么感觉。
and what I ought to say and what I ought to feel.
我有很多好老师。
I had a lot of good teachers.
我有很棒的父母,
I have wonderful parents,
有很多好人告诉我该怎么做。
had a lot of good people telling me what to do.
但这里有个案子
but here was a case
我将不得不自己做出这个决定。
where I was going to have to make this decision myself.
我觉得外面有很多人
and I think there's a lot of people out there
也许会有某种感觉
that maybe have a certain feeling
但它们没有捕捉到那种感觉
but they just don't capture that feeling
因为他们害怕别人会怎么想
because they're afraid of what people will think
他们不是，你知道，不是这么回事。
that they're not, you know, it's not what it's all about.
旁白: 虽然许多人挣扎
narrator: though many people struggled
如何应对战争，威明顿大学教授,
with how to respond to the war, wilmington college professor,
larry Gara 和他的妻子 Lenna Mae 没有。
larry gara and his wife lenna mae did not.
Gara 家族参与了大量的守夜活动
the gara's were involved in a plethora of vigils
以及越战期间的示威游行
and demonstrations during the vietnam war
而且对后果非常熟悉
and were quite familiar with the consequences
按照他们的信仰行事。
of acting upon their beliefs.
Larry 服过多次刑
larry served multiple prison sentences
他对体制的挑战,
for his challenges to the system,
从二战开始。
beginning during world war ii.
我只在越战期间被捕过一次。
larry: I was only arrested once during vietnam.
我不会轻视公民抗命。
I don't take civil disobedience lightly.
在1942年，当我应该注册的时候
and in 1942 when I was supposed to register
我别无选择，这是良心的问题。
I couldn't do anything else;
it was a matter of conscience.
我公开宣布我不能,
I publicly announced that I could not,
凭良心说，登记，当然当我这么做的时候,
in good conscience, register and of course when I did that,
我20岁的时候,
when I was 20 years old,
我被判入狱三年。
I was sentenced to prison for three years.
几年后，被指控为一名学生提供咨询服务
narrator: years later, accused of counseling a student
拒绝登记汇票,
to refuse to register for the draft,
加拉被判入狱18个月,
gara was sentenced to prison for another 18 months,
把他和他的妻子 Lenna Mae 分开。
separating him from his wife lenna mae.
那时我们已经结婚五六年了
lenna mae: we had been married for about five or six years then
这有点困难，非常困难,
and that was kind of difficult, very difficult,
但我年轻，他年轻,
but I was young, he was young,
我们很健康，我们挺过来了。
we were healthy, and we got through it.
我为自己做过的很多事感到后悔
larry: i've regret a lot of things i've done
但我从不后悔拒绝注册。
but I never regretted refusing to register.
我觉得这么做是绝对正确的
I think it was absolutely the right thing to do
仍然有这种感觉。
and still feel that way.
在越战期间,
narrator: throughout the vietnam war,
各地的贵格会教徒举行和平守夜,
Quakers everywhere held peace vigils,
1970年5月，辛辛那提和威明顿的朋友们
and in may 1970, cincinnati and wilmington friends
加入其他宗教团体抗议杀戮
joined other religious groups in protesting the killing
四个肯特州立大学的学生
of four kent state university students
俄亥俄州国民警卫队。
by the ohio national guard.
现任辛辛那提好友 Jim Crocker-lakness,
current cincinnati friends member, jim crocker-lakness,
was a student at kent state.
他记得那天早上。
he remembers that morning.
吉姆: 警卫进入了围栏区
jim: the guard moved into the fenced in area
发现自己被堵住了，动弹不得。
and found themselves blocked, couldn't move.
所以有那么一瞬间,
so there was a moment of back and forth between,
我们大概有八到十个人，在停车场。
about eight to ten of us, in the parking lot.
国民警卫队会发射催泪瓦斯
the national guard would shoot their tear gas
我们顺利排除了催泪瓦斯
and we were able to run down wind of the tear gas
捡起来扔回去。
and pick it up and throw it back.
然后我发现，我捡起了一块石头
and then I found myself-- I had picked up a rock
我发现我的胳膊翘起来准备扔这块石头
and I found my arm cocked ready to throw this rock
时间静止了。
and time stood still.
宇宙消失了，我听到耶稣说,
the universe vanished and I heard jesus say,
jim 你确定要这么做吗？
"jim are you sure you want to do that?
放下石头，跟我来”
drop that rock and follow me."
所以我的战争出于道义原因而拒服兵役者
and so my conscientious objection to war
基于耶稣教义的非暴力,
and non-violence based on the teachings of jesus,
回到我身边，我把石头扔了。
came back to me and I did drop the rock.
另一个有影响力的贵格会教徒
narrator: another influential Quaker actively involved
在和平证词之后的是 Wallace Collett,
in following the peace testimony was wallace collett,
来自俄亥俄州威尔明顿的二战时期依良心拒服兵役者。
a wwii conscientious objector from wilmington, ohio.
从威明顿学院毕业后,
after graduating from wilmington college,
collett 搬去了辛辛那提,
collett moved to cincinnati,
在那里他成为了一个杰出的商人和市民领袖。
where he became a prominent businessman and civic leader.
并最终成为主席
and eventually became chairman
美国朋友服务委员会的成员。
of the american friends service committee.
Wallace 很坦率,
paul: wallace was upfront,
公开反对战争税。
out in the open with his war tax resistance.
每年他都会填写他的1040
every year he would fill out his 1040
然后他会写下一张纸条
and he'd get to the bottom and he'd write a note
并附上它，告诉国税局，他没有支付 X 美元
and attach it, telling the irs that he had not paid x dollars
因为他认为它们是美元
because he considered them to be dollars
支持军队。
that supported the military.
但后来他继续说下去，他会告诉他们
but then he went on and he would tell them
我存了那么多钱
"i have deposited that amount of money
加上10% 的罚金
"plus whatever you know
10% for the penalties
我知道你会评估的
"that I know you are going to assess
加上可能到期的利息。
"plus any interest that might be due.
我把钱都存在这个银行账户里了。”
I put it all in this bank account."
他会告诉他们银行名字和账号
he'd give them the bank name and the account number
这样他们就能拿到钱了。
so they could go and get that money.
所以他打算抵制税收。
so he was going to resist the taxes.
他知道他们会想要的
he knew that they were going to want it
他不会阻止他们得到它。
and he wasn't gonna try to stop them from getting it.
事实上，他最终付出了更多，因为他知道他们
in fact he ended up paying more because he knew they were
评估罚款和利息。
going to assess penalties and interest on it.
所有的钱都在银行里，但他做了别的事。
all that money was in the bank, but then he did something else.
这才是精彩的部分。
this is the good part.
他认识辛辛那提大部分银行的总裁,
he knew the presidents of most of the banks in cincinnati,
也许是辛辛那提所有的银行。
maybe all the banks in cincinnati.
他会在银行开个账户，把钱存进去,
he would open an account at the bank, put the money in,
然后他会预约
but then he'd make an appointment
和银行行长谈话
with the president of the bank
他会走进去说“嗨 Al 你好吗?”？
and he would go in and he'd say, "hi al, how are you doing?
很高兴见到你。
"it's good to see you.
听着，国税局要来了
"listen the irs is going to come
他们会没收我的账户。”
and they are going to seize my account."
你可以想象这会引起多大的震惊。
well, you can imagine the shock that this would cause.
我的意思是，这是我们社区里的一个永久性的人
I mean, this is a permanent person in our community
他以银行行长的身份告诉我
and he is telling me as the president of the bank
他们会来没收他的财产。
that they are going to come and seize his assets.
当然，作为总统我该怎么做？
and so of course what do I do as the president?
我问你为什么，发生什么事了？
I said why, what's going on?
Wallace 就有机会告诉他们
and wallace would then have the opportunity to tell them
战争税代表了什么,
about what war taxes represented,
为什么他们错了，他做了什么来反抗他们。
why they were wrong and what he was doing to resist them.
这让他有机会为杰出人士服务,
it gave him an opportunity to minister to prominent people,
在商界有权有势的人
people with power and authority in the business community
我只是觉得这是个很好的例子
and I just think that's just such a tremendous example
为了我们所有人。
for all of us.
这些年来，其他人喜欢 Jim Crocker-lakness
narrator: over the years, others like jim crocker-lakness
面临着与和平证词有关的艰难抉择。
faced difficult choices related to the peace testimony.
Ryan Myers 的情况就是这样
such was the situation of ryan myers
在1990年的沙漠风暴中。
during desert storm in 1990.
但是在朋友的指导下
but after some guidance from fellow friend
以及出于良心拒服兵役者，查理・皮尔森,
and conscientious objector, charlie pierson,
迈尔斯对自己的决定更有信心。
myers was more confident in his decision.
考虑到要注册选择性服务,
ryan: looking at having to register for selective service,
我不会这么做的。
that I was not going to.
Charlie Pearson 也是会议成员之一
so charlie pearson, who was a member of the meeting
二战期间我是个狱警,
I was a co during wwii,
是我小时候的导师。
was a bit of mentor for me when I was young.
我想我从中获得了力量
I think I took some strength from that
我了解 Charlie 我尊重 Charlie。
knowing that, okay I know charlie and I respect charlie.
他做到了，他没事。
he was able to do it, he was okay.
当然，在我做决定的时候
of course, when I was making the decision
我知道这会带来潜在的法律后果。
I knew it carried potential legal consequences.
可能会被处以巨额罚款,
the possibility of a pretty substantial fine,
坐牢，而且我没有资格申请助学贷款。
prison time, and i'm not eligible for student loans.
但我觉得这对我来说是正确的决定。
but I think it was the right decision for me.
我想如果情况相同的话
I think if the circumstances were the same
我会再做一次决定。
i'd make the decision again.
[音乐]
[music]
近年来，一些贵格会教徒,
narrator: in recent years, some Quakers have,
就像他们的前辈一样,
as their predecessors did,
重点关注提供教育平等的项目。
focused on projects to provide education equality.
在当地朋友会议的支持下,
with the support of her local friends meeting,
辛辛那提贵格会教徒 Cathy Barney 把她的精力
cincinnati Quaker cathy barney has put her energy
进入一个为贫困儿童设立的艺术项目。
into an arts program for underprivileged children.
我开始是因为我知道有孩子
cathy: I started it because I just knew that there were kids
在我家附近
in my neighborhood
没有选择和机会
that didn't have the options and opportunities
普通孩子都有的,
that the average kid has,
但这些孩子同样有价值。
yet these kids were just as valuable.
我希望为这些孩子提供一个安全的地方,
I hope to provide a safe place for these kids,
我希望这能激发他们的灵感。
I hope it sparks something in them.
也许会有一个领域或者机会出现
that maybe an area or opportunity would open up
他们以前从未见过的东西。
that they hadn't seen before.
这只是一种发挥创造力的方式
donovan: it's just a way to be creative
把手弄脏。
and get your hands dirty.
我们画了些东西，还买了顶帽子
mckenzee: we painted stuff and we got like one of those hats
艺术家穿的衣服。
that the artists wear.
有些孩子告诉我
cathy: some of the kids have told me
他们真的很喜欢来这里，因为这能让他们
they really like to come here because it gets them
远离他们生活的日常生活。
away from the daily drama where they live.
我一直回来，因为有时候
angel: I keep coming back because sometimes
当我心情不好的时候，这是我唯一能去的地方
when I like have a bad day, this is the only place I can go to
让我感觉好多了。
and it like makes me feel better about myself.
我想 Cathy 想 Pat 他们都在教我
I miss cathy and miss pat and all of them teaching me
生活中重要的责任和事情。
the important responsibilities and stuff in life.
我认为这真的给了他们一种声音，一种自我表达。
cathy: I think it really gives them a voice, self expression.
如果这些孩子有自我表达的场所
if these kids have a venue for self expression
那他们就知道自己是谁了,
then they know who they are,
他们有发言权，他们可以对坏的影响说不,
they have a voice and they can say no to bad influences,
他们知道自己是谁。
they know who they are.
我觉得这会让他们更强大。
I think it makes them stronger.
如果我能学到点什么,
donovan: if I would learn something,
而是如何帮助别人
it would be how to help people
教人们怎么做艺术。
and teach people how to do the art stuff.
我就像变了一个人,
angel: i'm just like a different person,
好像我更成熟，也知道如何更好地处理情况。
like i'm more mature and I know how to handle situations better.
凯茜: 我认为贵格会教徒的原则之一
cathy: I think one of the Quaker principles
一直跟我说话的就是在别人身上看到上帝的影子
that has always spoken to me is seeing that of God in others
能在这些孩子身上看到上帝的影子
and being able to see that of God in these kids
帮助他们看到自己的优点。
and helping them to see that in themselves.
我的意思是，我认为，某种程度上，简而言之,
I mean, I think that's, sort of, in a nutshell,
重点是什么。
what the whole point is.
同样得到辛辛那提朋友会的支持,
narrator: also supported by cincinnati friends meeting,
luke 和 Angela Ebner 表达了他们的信仰
luke and angela ebner express their faith
通过和市中心的年轻人一起工作,
through work with inner city youth,
让他们接触有机物和永续园艺
exposing them to organic and sustainable gardening,
“播下希望的种子”
"planting seeds of hope."
和我们一起工作的孩子
luke: the kids that work with us
学习如何种植植物,
get to learn how to plant plants,
收获，销售，烹饪有机水果和蔬菜
harvest, market, cook organic fruits and vegetables
都长在这里。
that are all grown right here.
我总是说，我们种植有营养的栖息地
I always say we're planting nourishing habitats
为了我们的社区。
for our community.
所以这是一个滋养的栖息地，我得到培养
so this is a nourishing habitat that I get to cultivate
和我们接触的年轻人。
with the youth that we interact with.
生活在城市社区真的很难
robert: living in an urban community it's really hard
享受那段调解与和平的时光
to have that time of mediation and peace
因为总是有那么多事情发生。
because there's always so much going on.
这里人口稠密。
and this is a highly populated area.
所以像园艺这样隐蔽的地方,
so being in a secluded area like gardening,
它带给你一种你从来不知道存在的平静。
it brings you a peace that you never even knew existed.
能够种植粮食真是一件幸事
and it's truly a blessing to be able to grow food
因为工作需要而退出
and to just be out because putting your hands at work
真正让你的思想沉思和流畅
and really allow your mind to meditate and just flow
在草丛中迷失自我
and losing yourself while being in the grass
或者照料植物之类的
or tending to the plants or whatnot
你真的有机会去思考。
you really get the opportunity to think.
花园外的生活就像是一个挑战。
rashawn: life outside the garden is much like a challenge.
就像在花园里工作一样。
it's much like working at the garden.
就像我说的，努力做任何你想做的事
like I said, putting forth effort to do anything you want
需要练习、努力工作和奉献精神。
takes practice, hard work, and dedication.
我曾经无处可去。
robert: there was a time in my life when I had nowhere to go.
我不得不来到这个花园 Luke 给了我一份工作,
and I had to come to this garden and luke gave me a job,
他确保我口袋里有钱,
he made sure I had money in my pocket,
他确保这些钱足够我养家糊口。
he made sure it was enough for me to help support my family.
这个花园对我来说就是一切，真的。
this garden means everything to me, truly.
我在这里工作时学到的关于平等的知识
what i've learned about equality while working here
在生态园里，我们都在同一条船上,
at the eco garden is that we all are in the same boat,
没有人比别人更好。
no one is better than no one else.
即使有人可能有更好的衣服
even though someone might have better clothes
或者有更好的职业或者更好的选择
or might have a better career or better options
或者机会，在一天结束的时候
or opportunities, at the end of the day
我们都是有着相同缺点和问题的人。
we're all human beings with the same faults and issues.
说到底，我们害怕的东西是一样的。
at the end of the day, we're all afraid of the same things.
所以真的没有必要看到你上面的人
so truly there's no point in seeing anyone above you
或者在你之下，没有任何不安全感
or below you, there's no point of insecurity
因为我们都在同一条船上,
because we're all in the same boat,
我们都害怕同一件事,
we're all scared of the same thing,
我们都在寻找同样的东西。
we all seek the same thing.
旁白: 公众朋友兼部长，多恩・海登,
narrator: public friend and minister, donne hayden,
认为有几样东西特别吸引人
believes that several things particularly attract people
到贵格会: 社会行动主义
to Quakerism: social activism
以及“每个人心中都有上帝的旨意”的肯定
and the affirmation that there is "that of God in everyone"
其中包括理解
which includes the understanding
任何人都可以被上帝引导。
that anyone may be led or guided by God.
我们吸引那些深度参与的人
donne: we attract people who are deeply involved
有社会意识，致力于社会正义。
and socially conscious and committed to social justice.
但是另一种人是一个收听节目的人
but the other kind of person is a person who is tuned in
听着，能听到,
and listening and can hear,
或者可以被领导，因此发现自己与其他人在一起
or can be led and so finds themselves among others
他们有着相似的领导地位。
who are of similar leading.
对我来说，对我的家庭来说，这就是平等
julie: for me, for my family, that component of equality
是我们留在这里的原因之一。
has been a large piece of what has kept us here.
贵格会对我们帮助很大
rachel: Quakerism has really helped us
把注意力集中在外面,
focus ourselves outwards,
因为你可以看到它对其他人的影响
because you can see the effect that it has on everybody else
你觉得你在为社会做贡献
and you feel like you're contributing to society
帮助别人。
and helping others.
朱迪: 贵格会教徒认为我们每个人都有责任
judy: Quakers believe that each of us has the responsibility
成为一名牧师
to become a minister
并以我们自己的方式为社区服务
and to minister each in our own way to the community
以及更广阔的世界。
and to the wider world as well.
我对贵格会的迷恋一直都是暗地里的
jeff: my attraction to Quakerism has always been on the side
对宗教的经验方法,
of the experiential approach to religion,
你有一种即时的体验
that you have an immediate experience
灵魂的存在
of the presence of the spirit
从中培养出你的价值观和承诺。
and out of that grows your values and your commitments.
我刚发现你可以拥有一个真正的
rebecca: it is just discovering that you can have an actual
和你的创造者建立一对一的关系，你可以
one-on-one relationship with your creator and that you can
知道快乐与和平,
know the joy and the peace,
以及上帝创造我们的美丽。
and the beauty that God created us to know.
三个多世纪以来,
narrator: through more than three centuries,
到处都是教友会信徒，无名无姓,
Quakers everywhere-- famous and anonymous,
在东海岸城市和中西部乡村
in east coast city and midwestern countryside--
听从了 George Fox 的警告
have heeded george fox's admonition
“回答每个人心中的上帝”
to "answer that of God in everyone."
托马斯: 如果贵格会教徒应该感到骄傲的话,
thomas: if it were proper for Quakers to be proud,
我认为我们有资格为很多方面感到骄傲
I think we're entitled to be proud for the many ways
我们努力让世界变得更美好
that we've worked to try to make the world a better place
特别关注那些被边缘化的人
and particularly focused on people who were marginalized
被大社会剥夺了公民权。
and disenfranchised by the larger society.
我希望这对朋友来说永远是真的,
and I hope that's something that will always be true of friends,
我们将永远愿意成为反文化的,
that we will always be willing to be counter-cultural,
不是为了显得古怪
not for the sake of being odd
或者只是为了与众不同,
or just for the sake of being different,
而是因为与更大的文化背道而驰
but because by running counter to the larger culture
以及它的价值观，我们最终将它推向
and its values, we ultimately move it toward being
一个更美好、更公正、更彻底的公平世界。
a better, more just, more radically fair world.